<Version><xmlsource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlsource><Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General"><Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Health plan members' satisfaction with care: parents' or guardians' overall ratings of their children's specialist.&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CAHPS® health plan survey and reporting kit 2008. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2009 Jan. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field Name ="UMLS Concepts"><FieldValue Value="MSH: Child Health Services ; Consumer Satisfaction ; Health Care Surveys ; Managed Care Programs ; Physician-Patient Relations ; Professional-Patient Relations "/><FieldValue Value="MTH: Child Health Services ; Medical Specialities "/><FieldValue Value="SNOMEDCT_US: Medical specialty "/></Field></Section><Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain"><Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Patient Experience" /></Field><Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract"><Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess parents' or guardians' perceptions of their child's specialist. Parents rate their child's specialist on a scale from 0 to 10, where 0 is the worst specialist possible and 10 is the best specialist possible. Responses are grouped by rating: percentages are reported for ratings of 9 and 10, 7 and 8, and 6 and lower.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The percentage of ratings for the group 9 and 10 (or sometimes 8, 9, and 10) is used for consumer-level reporting; higher percentages indicate better quality. Additionally, frequency distributions encompassing all groups of ratings (i.e., 9 and 10, 7 and 8, 6 or lower) are available for plans or providers to use for quality improvement purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) (then called the Agency for Health Care Policy and Research, or AHCPR) initiated the CAHPS program in October 1995 to develop standardized survey tools for obtaining and reporting information on consumers' experiences with health care. The CAHPS consortium began by developing the CAHPS Health Plan Survey, an integrated set of carefully tested and standardized questionnaires and report formats that can be used to produce meaningful, reliable, and comparable information about the experiences of consumers enrolled in health plans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CAHPS Health Plan Survey is designed to generate information that consumers can use to choose health plans, that purchasers can use to assess the value of services they buy, and that health plans can use to assess their performance and improve their products and services. As AHRQ had intended, the survey can be used with all types of health insurance consumers--including Medicaid recipients, Medicare beneficiaries, and those who are commercially insured--and across the full range of health care delivery systems, from fee-for-service to managed care plans. The instruments also capture information about special groups, including individuals with chronic conditions and disabilities and families with children.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The National Committee for Quality Assurance (NCQA) requires health plans to submit measures from the CAHPS Health Plan Survey as part of their HEDIS submission and for accreditation purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Severyn Group. Personal communication. 2004 Apr 9. &amp;nbsp;13 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Specialist health provider; members' satisfaction&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health plan members age 17 years and younger whose parent or guardian answered the &quot;Rating of Specialist&quot; question on the CAHPS Health Plan Survey 4.0 (Child Questionnaire) (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parents' or guardians' ratings of their child's specialist on a scale from 0 to 10, where 0 is the worst specialist possible and 10 is the best specialist possible (see the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure"><Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="A formal consensus procedure, involving experts in relevant clinical, methodological,  public health and organizational sciences" /><FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" /></Field><Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the 2008 CAHPS Health Plan Survey Chartbook for the distribution of the CAHPS Health Plan Survey scores for each of the four ratings for the 3.0 Child Medicaid results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;What consumers say about the quality of their health plans and medical care: The National CAHPS Benchmarking Database. CAHPS health plan survey chartbook. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2008 Oct. 43 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CAHPS Health Plan Survey has probably been tested more completely than any previously used consumer survey.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two different and complementary approaches to assessing the reliability and validity of a questionnaire (1) cognitive testing, which bases its assessments on feedback from interviews with people who are asked to react to the survey questions, and (2) psychometric testing, which bases its assessments on the analysis of data collected by using the questionnaire. Although many existing consumer questionnaires about health care have been tested primarily or exclusively using a psychometric approach, the CAHPS team views the combination of cognitive and psychometric approaches as essential to producing the best possible survey instruments. Consequently, both methods have been included in the development of the CAHPS survey.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cognitive testing method provided useful information on respondents' perceptions of the response task, how respondents recalled and reported events, and how they interpreted specified reference periods. It also helped identify words that could be used to describe health care providers accurately and consistently across a range of consumers (e.g., commercially insured, Medicaid, fee-for-service, managed care, lower socioeconomic status [SES], middle SES, low literacy, higher literacy) and helped explore whether key words and concepts included in the core questions worked equally well in both English and Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CAHPS consortium also tested each CAHPS reporting composite in focus groups with plan members. Cognitive interviews with consumers were conducted to ensure that the reporting composites and their labels were easily understood. Psychometric analyses using data collected during pilot tests were also conducted. These analyses indicated that both the composites and the items in each composite were reliable and valid measures of members' experiences. In addition, items in each reporting composite were tested and found to be internally consistent. For example, reliability coefficients (Cronbach's alpha) in one pilot test involving four health plans using the instrument that most resembled the final CAHPS 2.0 instrument ranged from a low of 0.68 for the &amp;quot;Getting Needed Care&amp;quot; composite to a high of 0.90 for the &amp;quot;How Well Doctors Communicate&amp;quot; composite. These composites are positively associated with members' ratings of overall care provided by doctors and nurses and ratings of health plans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, the CAHPS development team, together with researchers from the National Committee on Quality Assurance (NCQA), conducted a detailed comparative analysis of the items in the CAHPS questionnaire and NCQA's Member Satisfaction Survey (MSS) from the fall of 1997 to the spring of 1998. These questionnaires were merged to form the 2.0 version of the CAHPS questionnaire. This testing is noteworthy because it was so extensive and because of the wide array of techniques used. These included focus groups, in-depth cognitive testing, pilot studies, methodological experiments, and large demonstration studies, such as the demonstrations in Washington State, Kansas, and New Jersey.  NCQA also worked with the CAHPS consortium to conduct field tests of the 4.0 instrument with six health plans in spring 2005.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CAHPS®: Surveys and tools to advance patient-centered care [https://www.cahps.ahrq.gov/default.asp]. [internet]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); [updated 2008 Feb 21]; [accessed 2007 Sep 05]. [3 p]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Current routine use" /></Field><Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use"><Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Managed Care Plans" /></Field><Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" /></Field><Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Specified" /></Field><Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age less than or equal to 17 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Either male or female" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care"><Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Health and Well-being of Communities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Person- and Family-centered Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories"><Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="End of Life Care" /><FieldValue Value="Getting Better" /><FieldValue Value="Living with Illness" /><FieldValue Value="Staying Healthy" /></Field><Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Patient-centeredness" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure"><Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;12 months or longer (commercial) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;6 months or longer (Medicaid) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Enrollees or beneficiaries" /></Field><Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Encounter" /><FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" /></Field><Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Health plan members age 17 years and younger who have been enrolled in:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The commercial plan for 12 months or longer, with no more than one 45-day break in enrollment during the 12 months&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A Medicaid plan or product for 6 months or longer, with no more than one 30-day break in enrollment during the 6 months. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AND&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whose parent or guardian answered the &quot;Rating of Specialist&quot; question on the CAHPS Health Plan Survey 4.0 (Child Questionnaire). Include refusals, non-response, and bad addresses/phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Individuals with coverage other than primary health coverage, such as dental-only plan &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Deceased &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Ineligible (not enrolled in the plan) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Parents' or guardians' ratings of their child's specialist on a scale from 0 to 10, where 0 is the worst specialist possible and 10 is the best specialist possible&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Responses are grouped by rating: percentages are reported for ratings of 9 and 10, 7 and 8, and 6 and lower.  The higher the percentage of ratings for the group 9 and 10 is associated with better quality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Include all completed questionnaires.  A questionnaire is considered complete if responses are available for 10 or more of a selected list of key CAHPS items.  Refer to the original measure documentation for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Fixed time period or point in time" /></Field><Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" /><FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual survey" /></Field><Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;CAHPS&amp;reg; Health Plan Survey 4.0, Child Questionnaire&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Composite/Scale" /></Field><Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" /></Field><Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3069" OrdBy="550" ID="611" Name="Description of Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;CAHPS recommends adjusting the data for respondent age, education, and general health status.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the sample size is sufficient, responses may be analyzed for specific sub-populations, such as respondents with chronic conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information"><Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rating of specialist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="CAHPS Health Plan Survey" /></Field><Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="CAHPS Health Plan Survey 4.0, Child Questionnaire" /></Field><Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" /></Field><Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p"><FieldValue Value="Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" /><FieldValue Value="CAHPS Consortium - Health Care Quality Collaboration" /><FieldValue Value="Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" /></Field><Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;American Institutes for Research (AIR) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Harvard Medical School &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;National Committee for Quality Assurance &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;RAND &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Westat &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date"><FieldValue Value="2009 Jan" /></Field><Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates a previous version: CAHPS&amp;reg; health plan survey and reporting kit 2007. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2006 Nov 14. Various p.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measure developer reaffirmed the currency of this measure in November 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The individual measure, &quot;Rating of Specialist,&quot; is published in the &quot;CAHPS&amp;reg; Health Plan Survey and Reporting Kit 2008.&quot; This Kit may be downloaded at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cahps.ahrq.gov/Surveys-Guidance/HP/Get-Surveys-and-Instructions.aspx&quot; title=&quot;CAHPS Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CAHPS Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cahps1@ahrq.hhs.gov&quot;&gt;CAHPS Technical Assistance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="15" OrdBy="790" ID="635" Name="Companion Documents" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;What consumers say about the quality of their health plans and medical care: The National CAHPS Benchmarking Database. CAHPS health plan survey chartbook. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2008 Oct. 43 p. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;CAHPS&amp;reg; user resources: project management resources. [internet]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); [updated 2008 Oct 29]; [accessed 2009 Mar 17]. [2 pages]. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The health care report card compendium. [internet]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); [updated 2011 Oct 26]; [accessed 2012 Jan 20]. [1 page]. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cahps.ahrq.gov/Consumer-Reporting/RCC.aspx&quot; title=&quot;CAHPS: The Health Care Report Card Compendium&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CAHPS Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;CAHPS&amp;reg; survey and reporting kits. Project profiles. [internet]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); [updated 2008 Oct 29]; [accessed 2009 Mar 17]. [2 pages]. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;CAHPS&amp;reg; survey and reporting kits. Reporting resources: downloadable documents. [internet]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); [updated 2009 Apr 23]; [accessed 2009 Mar 17]. [2 pages]. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The CAHPS Improvement Guide.[internet]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); [updated 2011 Nov 4]; [accessed 2012 Jan 20]. [1 page]. This document is available in (PDF) from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cahps.ahrq.gov/Quality-Improvement/Improvement-Guide.aspx&quot; title=&quot;The CAHPS Improvement Guide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CAHPS Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cahps1@ahrq.hhs.gov&quot;&gt;CAHPS Technical Assistance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI on April 24, 2007. The information was verified by the measure developer on June 15, 2007. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on May 18, 2009. The information was verified by the measure developer on August 14, 2009. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on April 29, 2011. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information was reaffirmed by the measure developer on November 5, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;No copyright restrictions apply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production"><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CAHPS® health plan survey and reporting kit 2008. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2009 Jan. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer"><Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the NQMC Inclusion Criteria which may be found at &lt;a href=&quot;../about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.qualitymeasures.ahrq.gov/about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" /></Field></Section></Version>
