<Version><xmlsource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlsource><Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General"><Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Dental plan members' experiences: adult dental plan members' ratings of their dental care.&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CAHPS Dental Plan Survey. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2009 Feb 10. 9 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Items in the reporting composites and overall ratings for the CAHPS Dental Plan survey. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2009 Feb. 2 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field Name ="UMLS Concepts"><FieldValue Value="MSH: Dental Care ; Dental Health Services ; Insurance, Dental ; Patient Satisfaction ; Physician-Patient Relations "/><FieldValue Value="MTH: Client satisfaction ; Dental Procedures "/><FieldValue Value="SNOMEDCT_US: Client satisfaction ; Dental-oral procedure AND/OR service "/></Field></Section><Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain"><Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Patient Experience" /></Field><Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract"><Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess adult dental plan patients' perceptions of their dental care. Patients rate dental care received on a scale from 0 to 10, where 0 is the worst dental care possible and 10 is the best dental care possible. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Typically, the percentage of ratings for the group 9 and 10 is used for consumer-level reporting; higher percentages indicate better quality. Additionally, frequency distributions encompassing all groups of ratings (i.e., 9 and 10, 7 and 8, 6 or lower) are available for plans or providers to use for quality improvement purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patient satisfaction is a common subject in the dental literature, and this partly seems to result from the unique nature of dental care.  Patients tend to suffer from a fair amount of anxiety related to dental care - most notably with respect to the pain and discomfort associated (at least subjectively) with many dental procedures. One survey in Kentucky found that 40% of the population reported dental fear, with 17% reporting high dental fear.  In that same study, 52% of the population were of the opinion that &quot;pain&quot; was the main reason that people were afraid of the dentist.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The literature also shows that the level of distress, anxiety, or fear appear to influence patients' evaluations of dentists' behaviors and patients' satisfaction with care.  Level of anxiety has even been shown to influence the kind of communication style preferred by the patient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pain itself is an important dimension of the dental patient experience, and it has been shown to influence care-seeking and compliance with treatment, increase feelings of helplessness, and predict patterns of health service utilization; patients' descriptions of pain can influence clinical judgments and treatment decisions (e.g., how much pain relief is offered to the patient).  Patients view pain as a &quot;discrete assessable component&quot; of dental treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Communication has been shown to be a significant influence on patient satisfaction.  Several studies emphasize the importance of dentist-patient interaction during the dental encounter - especially in terms of what has been labeled &quot;communicative involvement&quot; in one study.  Communicatively involved dentists appear attentive, perceptive, and responsive to patients' comments and needs; they establish rapport, discuss treatment plans and options, and help elaborate and confirm the patient's understanding of their treatment encounter.   This kind of open, interactive communication has been shown to improve the patient's overall satisfaction with their dental provider.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, it has been generally shown that a dentist's &quot;chairside manner&quot; significantly influences dental care outcomes such as patients' satisfaction, anxiety, and willingness to return for further treatment.  Patients who receive incomplete, general, or impersonal information regarding their condition of treatment tend to perceive their dentist as hostile.  This desire for information reflects the desire patients have to play a collaborative role in decision-making regarding their dental care, although many perceive that they play a passive role in treatment decisions.  In some cases, however, some patients (e.g., those who suffer from particularly high anxiety) do show a preference for interaction marked by &quot;communicative dominance&quot; on the practitioner's part, which refers to the extent to which the dentist controls the nature and topics of the encounter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another dimension is satisfaction with the results of dental treatment.  This dimension is to some extent concentrated in the specialty area of prosthodontics - the sub-field that deals with the restoration and replacement of teeth (e.g., fitting of dentures, implants, and bridges) - although these satisfaction concerns do span other areas of dentistry.  This dimension includes basic (improvement in) comfort experienced by the patient as a result of dental work, the functionality of prosthodontic dental work (e.g., in eating or chewing, or phonetics), as well as the overall appearance, or aesthetics, of prosthodontics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Allen PF, McMillan AS, Locker D. An assessment of sensitivity to change of the Oral Health Impact Profile in a clinical trial. Community Dent Oral Epidemiol. 2001 Jun;29(3):175-82. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=11409676&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bader JD, Shugars DA, White BA, Rindal DB. Evaluation of audit-based performance measures for dental care plans. J Public Health Dent. 1999 Summer;59(3):150-7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=10649587&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CAHPS dental survey: year one final report. To inform the CAHPS dental survey pilot project: a national effort to measure the dental health care experience in the MHS. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2005 Nov 21. 129 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Chapple H, Shah S, Caress AL, Kay EJ. Exploring dental patients' preferred roles in treatment decision-making - a novel approach. Br Dent J. 2003 Mar 22;194(6):321-7; discussion 317. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12682659&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;de Bruyn H, Collaert B, Linden U, Bjorn AL. Patient's opinion and treatment outcome of fixed rehabilitation on Branemark implants. A 3-year follow-up study in private dental practices. Clin Oral Implants Res. 1997 Aug;8(4):265-71. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=9586472&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hakestam U, Karlsson T, Soderfeldt B, Ryden O, Glantz PO. Does the quality of advanced prosthetic dentistry determine patient satisfaction. Acta Odontol Scand. 1997 Dec;55(6):365-71. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=9477029&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hegarty AM, McGrath C, Hodgson TA, Porter SR. Patient-centred outcome measures in oral medicine: are they valid and reliable. Int J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2002 Dec;31(6):670-4. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12521327&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Leitch JA, Sutcliffe N, Kenny GN. Patient-maintained sedation for oral surgery using a target-controlled infusion of propofol - a pilot study. Br Dent J. 2003 Jan 11;194(1):43-5. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12540939&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Lundgren S, Rosenquist JB. Comparison of sedation, amnesia, and patient comfort produced by intravenous and  rectal diazepam. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 1984 Oct;42(10):646-50. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=6592306&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Malmstrom HS, Chaves Y, Moss ME. Patient preference: conventional rotary handpieces or air abrasion for cavity preparation. Oper Dent. 2003 Nov-Dec;28(6):667-71. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=14653278&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Newton J, Brenneman D. Communication in Dental Settings Scale (CDSS): Preliminary development of a measure to assess communication in dental settings. Br J Health Psychol. 1999;4:277-84.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pau AK, Croucher R, Marcenes W. Perceived inability to cope and care-seeking in patients with toothache: a qualitative study. Br Dent J. 2000 Nov 11;189(9):503-6. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=11104104&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rankin JA, Harris MB. Patients' preferences for dentists' behaviors. J Am Dent Assoc. 1985 Mar;110(3):323-7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=3858344&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Riley JL 3rd, Myers CD, Robinson ME, Bulcourf B, Gremillion HA. Factors predicting orofacial pain patient satisfaction with improvement. J Orofac Pain. 2001 Winter;15(1):29-35. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=11889645&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Schropp L, Isidor F, Kostopoulos L, Wenzel A. Patient experience of, and satisfaction with, delayed-immediate vs. delayed single-tooth implant placement. Clin Oral Implants Res. 2004 Aug;15(4):498-503. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15248886&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sloan JA, Tolman DE, Anderson JD, Sugar AW, Wolfaardt JF, Novotny P. Patients with reconstruction of craniofacial or intraoral defects: development of instruments to measure quality of life. Int J Oral Maxillofac Implants. 2001 Mar-Apr;16(2):225-45. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=11324211&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Smith TA, Thompson JA, Lee WE. Assessing patient pain during dental laser treatment. J Am Dent Assoc. 1993 Feb;124(2):90-5. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=8429189&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Stahlnacke K, Soderfeldt B, Unell L, Halling A, Axtelius B. Perceived oral health: changes over 5 years in one Swedish age-cohort. Community Dent Oral Epidemiol. 2003 Aug;31(4):292-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12846852&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Street RL. Patients' satisfaction with dentists' communicative style. Health Commun. 1989;1(3):137-54.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Weinstein M, Schuchman J, Lieberman J, Rosen P. Age and denture experience as determinants in patient denture satisfaction. J Prosthet Dent. 1988 Mar;59(3):327-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=3162273&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Zimmerman RS. The dental appointment and patient behavior. Differences in patient and practitioner preferences, patient satisfaction, and adherence. Med Care. 1988 Apr;26(4):403-14. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=3352333&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adult dental care; patients' satisfaction with dental care received&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dental plan patients age 18 years and older who answered the &quot;Overall Ratings - Dental Care&quot; question on the CAHPS Dental Plan Survey&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients' ratings of their dental care they received on a scale from 0 to 10, where 0 is the worst dental care possible and 10 is the best dental care possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Higher ratings indicate better quality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure"><Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="A formal consensus procedure, involving experts in relevant clinical, methodological,  public health and organizational sciences" /><FieldValue Value="Focus groups" /><FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" /></Field><Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The design and testing of this tool were informed by the Consumer Assessment of Healthcare&#xD;&#xA;Providers and Systems (CAHPS) initiative. CAHPS is a public-private initiative begun in&#xD;&#xA;1994 and continuing through 2012 to develop a standard set of surveys of health care quality as&#xD;&#xA;experienced and reported by patients. Widespread adoption of these surveys by providers&#xD;&#xA;and/or systems is facilitated by the quality of the methods used to develop, test and disseminate them. These methods include rigorous scientific peer review of results, the involvement of key stakeholders in the design and testing of the surveys, and the distribution of surveys and supporting material free of charge at the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ) Web site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Keller S, Col Martin GC, Evensen CT, Capt Mitton RH. The development and testing of a survey instrument for benchmarking dental plan performance: using insured patients' experiences as a gauge of dental care quality. J Am Dent Assoc. 2009 Feb;140(2):229-37. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19188420&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Current routine use" /></Field><Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use"><Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Managed Care Plans" /></Field><Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" /></Field><Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Unspecified" /></Field><Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 18 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Either male or female" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care"><Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Health and Well-being of Communities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Person- and Family-centered Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories"><Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Getting Better" /><FieldValue Value="Staying Healthy" /></Field><Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Patient-centeredness" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure"><Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Enrollees or beneficiaries" /></Field><Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Encounter" /><FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" /></Field><Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Dental plan patients age 18 years and older who answered the &quot;Overall Ratings - Dental Care&quot; question on the CAHPS Dental Plan Survey&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Patients' ratings of their dental care they received on a scale from 0 to 10, where 0 is the worst dental care possible and 10 is the best dental care possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Higher ratings indicate better quality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Fixed time period or point in time" /></Field><Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual survey" /></Field><Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;CAHPS Dental Plan Survey&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Composite/Scale" /></Field><Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" /></Field><Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3069" OrdBy="550" ID="611" Name="Description of Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To fairly compare your dental plan's results to those of other dental plans, we adjusted the results for differences in respondent characteristics across dental plans. These are characteristics that could change the way a patient responds to the survey regardless of their care experience; in this case: patients' age, education, and self-reported health. For example, individuals in better health and older individuals have tended to rate their care and the setting in which they receive their care higher than individuals who are younger and in poorer health. The adjusted results are those we would expect for each dental plan, if they had similar patients. For this report, the results were case-mix adjusted by respondents' age, education, and overall health status following standard CAHPS methods that have been subject to rigorous development and testing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information"><Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall ratings - dental care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="CAHPS Dental Plan Survey" /></Field><Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" /></Field><Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p"><FieldValue Value="Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" /><FieldValue Value="CAHPS Consortium - Health Care Quality Collaboration" /></Field><Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;TRICARE Management Authority&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date"><FieldValue Value="2009 Feb" /></Field><Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measure developer reaffirmed the currency of this measure in July 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The individual measure, &quot;Overall Ratings - Dental Care,&quot; is published in the &quot;CAHPS Dental Plan Survey,&quot; available for download at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cahps.ahrq.gov/Surveys-Guidance/Dental.aspx&quot; title=&quot;CAHPS Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CAHPS Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cahps1@ahrq.hhs.gov&quot;&gt;CAHPS Technical Assistance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on February 11, 2010. The information was verified by the measure developer on April 8, 2010. This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on April 21, 2011. The information was reaffirmed by the measure developer on July 22, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;No copyright restrictions apply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production"><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CAHPS Dental Plan Survey. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2009 Feb 10. 9 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Items in the reporting composites and overall ratings for the CAHPS Dental Plan survey. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2009 Feb. 2 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer"><Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the NQMC Inclusion Criteria which may be found at &lt;a href=&quot;../about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.qualitymeasures.ahrq.gov/about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" /></Field></Section></Version>
