<Version><xmlsource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlsource><Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General"><Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Chronic stable coronary artery disease: percentage of patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of coronary artery disease seen within a 12 month period for whom there are documented results of an evaluation of level of activity AND an evaluation of presence or absence of anginal symptoms in the medical record.&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association, Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement®. Chronic stable coronary artery disease performance measurement set. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2011 Jan. 95 p.  [75 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field Name ="UMLS Concepts"><FieldValue Value="ICD9CM: Coronary atherosclerosis of native coronary artery  (414.01); Other and unspecified angina pectoris  (413.9)"/><FieldValue Value="MSH: Angina Pectoris ; Chronic Disease ; Coronary Artery Disease ; Documentation ; Motor Activity ; Office Visits "/><FieldValue Value="MTH: Angina Pectoris ; Chronic disease ; Coronary Artery Disease ; Documentation ; Physical activity "/><FieldValue Value="SNOMEDCT_US: Chronic disease ; Chronic disease of cardiovascular system ; Disorder of coronary artery ; Ischemic chest pain ; Patient evaluation and management ; Physical activity "/></Field></Section><Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain"><Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Process" /></Field><Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract"><Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the percentage of patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of coronary artery disease seen within a 12 month period for whom there are documented results of an evaluation of level of activity AND an evaluation of presence or absence of anginal symptoms in the medical record.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This measure and the Symptom Management measure (see the related National Quality Measures Clearinghouse [NQMC] summary &lt;a href=&quot;/content.aspx?id=34943&amp;amp;search=%23%237238&quot; title=&quot;Measure Summary&quot;&gt;Chronic stable coronary artery disease: percentage of patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of coronary artery disease seen within a 12 month period and with results of an evaluation of level of activity AND an evaluation of presence or absence of anginal symptoms, with appropriate management of anginal symptoms [evaluation of level of activity and symptoms includes no report of anginal symptoms OR evaluation of level of activity and symptoms includes report of anginal symptoms and a plan of care is documented to achieve control of anginal symptoms]&lt;/a&gt;) address related aspects of care for effective assessment and management of symptoms for a patient with chronic stable coronary artery disease. The intent of these measures is that they be utilized as a pair, as the results of the Symptom &amp;amp; Activity Assessment provide the basis of decisions that are made in the Symptom Management measure. It is not recommended that either of these measures be used independently. The pairing of these measures is not intended to suggest the use of any particular scoring methodology (i.e., a composite score), nor does it imply either equality of difference in the relative &quot;weights&quot; of the two measures. A performance score for each measure should be reported individually. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;The National Quality Forum (NQF) provides definitions of paired and composite measures:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Paired measures are individual measures that should be measured concurrently in the same population; however, the results are not combined into a single score (e.g., measuring mortality and readmission and displaying them together&amp;mdash;but not calculating a joint score). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A composite measure is a combination of two or more individual measures in a single measure that results in a single score. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to effectively manage the symptoms of a patient with chronic stable coronary artery disease, an assessment of those symptoms needs to be performed. This assessment is the basis of any treatment modification that needs to be made. Effective management of the symptoms associated with chronic stable coronary artery disease (e.g., chest pain, shortness of breath) may lead to improved patient quality of life which is an important, patient-centered outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;The following evidence statements are quoted &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;verbatim&lt;/span&gt; from the referenced clinical guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;The treatment of chronic stable angina has two complementary objectives: to reduce the risk of mortality and morbid events and to reduce symptoms. From the patient's perspective, it is often the latter that is of greater concern. The cardinal symptom of [coronary artery disease (CAD)] is anginal chest pain or equivalent symptoms, such as exertional dyspnea. Often the patient suffers not only from discomfort of the symptom itself but also from accompanying limitations on activities and the associated anxiety that the symptoms may produce. (Serves as a basis for treatment modification.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association, Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement®. Chronic stable coronary artery disease performance measurement set. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2011 Jan. 95 p.  [75 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Gibbons RJ, Abrams J, Chatterjee K, Daley J, Deedwania PC, Douglas JS, Ferguson TB Jr, et al. ACC/AHA 2002 guideline update for the management of patients with chronic stable angina. A report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines (Committee to update the 1999 guidelines). Reston (VA): American College of Cardiology, American Heart Association; 2002. 126 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coronary artery disease; anginal symptom assessment; level of activity assessment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of coronary artery disease seen within a 12 month period (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients for whom there are documented results of an evaluation of level of activity AND an evaluation of presence or absence of anginal symptoms in the medical record (see the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure"><Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" /><FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" /></Field><Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance of Topic&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prevalence and Incidence&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;16.3 million Americans are living with coronary heart disease. Total coronary heart disease prevalence is 7.0% in adults aged 20 years and older in the United States (U.S.). Prevalence of coronary heart disease for men is 8.3% and for women is 6.1%. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Coronary heart disease makes up more than half of all cardiovascular events in men and women less than 75 years of age. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The lifetime risk of developing coronary heart disease after age 40 is 49% for men and 32% for women. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The incidence of coronary heart disease in women lags behind men by 10 years for total coronary heart disease and by 20 years for more serious clinical events such as myocardial infarction (MI) and sudden death. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mortality&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;While death rates have fallen from 1968 to the present, coronary heart disease is the largest killer of men and women in the U.S. It has been estimated that approximately 47% of this decrease is attributed to treatments (medical and surgical), while approximately 44% is attributed to changes in risk factors. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Coronary heart disease caused approximately 1 of every 6 deaths in the U.S. in 2007. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Approximately 81% of people who die of coronary heart disease are greater than or equal to 65 years of age. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The mortality rate for women age 35 to 44 increased on average by 1.3% per year between 1997 and 2002. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Since 1984, the number of deaths for women has exceeded those for men; in 2005, women represented 52.6% of deaths from coronary heart disease. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;People who have had a MI have a sudden death rate 4 to 6 times that of the general population. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Office Visits&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;2008 data found that the number of ambulatory care visits for coronary heart disease was 16,251,000. The majority of these visits (62.2%) were for coronary atherosclerosis. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cost &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In 2007, the estimated direct and indirect cost for coronary heart disease in the U.S. is $177.5 billion. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In 2006, coronary artery disease was the most expensive condition treated in U.S. hospitals at a cost of $52.6 billion and accounted for 5% of total hospitalization costs. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Thirty percent of Medicare's total expenditures are applied to cardiovascular disease. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In 2007, $5.2 billion was spent on outpatient visits related to chronic ischemic heart disease. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opportunity for Improvement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to a study analyzing the quality of care in the U.S., on average, patients with coronary artery disease received the recommended quality of care 68% of the time. Quality of care was assessed by analysis of clinician performance on thirty-seven coronary artery disease quality indicators. Quality of care varied significantly by indicator with average rates of adherence ranging from 29.13% for counseling for smoking cessation at the time of coronary artery disease diagnosis to 100% for left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) assessment of patients hospitalized with MI either during hospitalization or within two weeks of hospital discharge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A study conducted by Ho et al. found that nonadherence to cardioprotective medications was prevalent among outpatients with coronary artery disease and was associated with a broad range of adverse outcomes, including all-cause and cardiovascular mortality, cardiovascular hospitalizations, and the need for revascularization procedures. Although there have been improvements in the prescription rates of secondary prevention medications for coronary artery disease patients, a gap persists between the benefits demonstrated with these medications in clinical trials and the effectiveness observed in clinical practice. One potential explanation for this discrepancy is suboptimal adherence to secondary prevention medications in practice compared with clinical trials, where adherence is often closely monitored. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Over a median follow up of 4.1 years, medication nonadherence to statins, angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitors, and beta-blockers was common, occurring in approximately 1 in 4 patients. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Among patients dispensed beta-blockers (n = 11,865), 28.8% were nonadherent. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;For patients dispensed ACE inhibitors or angiotensin-receptor blockers (ARBs) (n = 10,021), 21.6% were nonadherent. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;For patients taking statin medications (n = 13,596), 26.0% were nonadherent. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In another study conducted by Apikoglu Rabus and colleagues, 73 patients who were diagnosed to have coronary artery disease were followed up for 5 years. They concluded there was suboptimal prescribing of secondary prevention drugs and absence of continuity of prescribing these secondary prevention drugs in the pharmaceutical care of coronary artery disease patients. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The 'initial prescribing rate' at discharge was found to be 82% for aspirin, 49% for statins, 44% for ACE inhibitors and 55% for beta-blockers. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;'Continuity of prescribing' for 5 years was 45% for aspirin, 26% for statins, 17% for ACE inhibitors and 20% for beta-blockers. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cardiac rehabilitation programs remain underused. In the U.S., only 10-20% of the 2 million eligible patients per year who experience myocardial infarction or underwent cardiac revascularization procedures participated in cardiac rehabilitation programs. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A recently published study that was set in Australian primary care practices found that patients with stable angina who reported weekly anginal symptoms had worse quality of life and greater physical limitations compared to those reporting minimal anginal symptoms. Additionally, patients reporting weekly anginal symptoms varied across the clinic sites, highlighting potential differences in the identification of management of angina by site of care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association, Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement®. Chronic stable coronary artery disease performance measurement set. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2011 Jan. 95 p.  [75 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Andrews RM. The national hospital bill: the most expensive conditions by payer, 2006. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2008. &amp;nbsp;(Statistical Brief; no. 59).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Apikoglu Rabus S, Izzettin FV, Sancar M, Karakaya O, Kargin R, Yakut C. Five-year follow-up of drug utilization for secondary prevention in coronary artery disease. Pharm World Sci. 2008 Dec;30(6):753-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18563622&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Beltrame JF, Weekes AJ, Morgan C, Tavella R, Spertus JA. The prevalence of weekly angina among patients with chronic stable angina in primary care practices: The Coronary Artery Disease in General Practice (CADENCE) Study. Arch Intern Med. 2009 Sep 14;169(16):1491-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19752407&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services. Table 10.4: Hospital outpatient bills, covered charges, and program payments under medicare by selected reasons for the visit: calendar year 2007. In: Health Care Financing Review: Medicare &amp; Medicaid Statistical Supplement. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services; 2008. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ho PM, Magid DJ, Shetterly SM, Olson KL, Maddox TM, Peterson PN, Masoudi FA, Rumsfeld JS. Medication nonadherence is associated with a broad range of adverse outcomes in patients with coronary artery disease. Am Heart J. 2008 Apr;155(4):772-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18371492&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Levit K, Stranges E, Ryan K, Elixhauser A. HCUP facts and figures, 2006: statistics on hospital-based care in the United States. [internet]. Rockville (MD):  Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality; 2008&amp;nbsp;[accessed 2009 May 06]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;McGlynn EA, Asch SM, Adams J, Keesey J, Hicks J, DeCristofaro A, Kerr EA. The quality of health care delivered to adults in the United States. N Engl J Med. 2003 Jun 26;348(26):2635-45. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12826639&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Roger VL, Go AS, Lloyd-Jones DM, Adams RJ, Berry JD, Brown TM, Carnethon MR, Dai S, de Simone G, Ford ES, Fox CS, Fullerton HJ, Gillespie C, Greenlund KJ, Hailpern SM, Heit JA, Ho PM, Howard VJ, Kissela BM, Kittner SJ, Lackland DT, Lichtman JH, Lisabeth LD, Makuc DM, Marcus GM, Marelli A, Matchar DB, McDermott MM, Meigs JB, Moy CS, Mozaffarian D, Mussolino ME, Nichol G, Paynter NP, Rosamond WD, Sorlie PD, Stafford RS, Turan TN, Turner MB, Wong ND, Wylie-Rosett J. Heart disease and stroke statistics--2011 update: a report from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2011 Feb 1;123(4):e18-209. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=21160056&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Spronk S, Bosch JL, Ryjewski C, Rosenblum J, Kaandorp GC, White JV, Hunink MG. Cost-effectiveness of new cardiac and vascular rehabilitation strategies for patients with coronary artery disease. PLoS ONE. 2008;3(12):e3883. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19065259&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Trogdon JG, Finkelstein EA, Nwaise IA, Tangka FK, Orenstein D. The economic burden of chronic cardiovascular disease for major insurers. Health Promot Pract. 2007 Jul;8(3):234-42. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17606951&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association/Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement (ACC/AHA/PCPI) coronary artery disease measures, in their previous specifications, have been utilized in several national performance measurement projects, including the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) Physician Group Practice (PGP) Demonstration Project, the Doctors' Office Quality (DOQ) Project, the DOQ Information Technology (DOQ-IT) Project, the CMS Physician Quality Reporting Initiative (PQRI) program, and the CMS Electronic Health Records (EHRs) Demonstration Project. These projects have shown varying levels of feasibility, reliability, and performance, dependent upon the venue and modality of data collection. In addition, specific research projects have been conducted to test the reliability of these measures in various settings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feasibility Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CMS DOQ Project revealed that the majority of measures studied from the coronary artery disease set are feasible to collect, as previously specified. As part of the DOQ project, reviewers assessed the feasibility of use of the ACC/AHA/PCPI measures in offices by performing retrospective audits of paper medical records and electronic health records. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Implementation of two of the coronary artery disease measures in the PQRI program allowed for tracking of denominator mismatch rates. It is important to note that physicians participating in PQRI for coronary artery disease measures in 2007 represented a small proportion of the eligible physicians (6.52-9.87%) and therefore the measure performance rates may not accurately reflect the ability of the general physician population to attain quality performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The DOQ project tested inter-rater reliability twice during the project. The agreement rate for the coronary artery disease measures was 95.2%.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a 2001 pilot test of the measures, a random sample of 100 medical records for patients with confirmed diagnosis of coronary artery disease were reviewed by two trained abstractors. Medical records were selected from 4 physician practices, which were a mixture of cardiology practices and primary care practices located in urban and rural areas. Overall reliability rate for all participating practices was 98.1%, with reliability rates for individual data elements ranging from 0.82 to 1.00. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A study by Persell et al. compared automated measure abstraction and calculation of EHR data against measure calculation based on manual review of electronic notes for patients with apparent quality deficits. Performance based on automated review of EHR data ranged between 81.6% and 97.6%. Automated review plus manual review of free text physician notes for cases that failed quality measures shifted the performance range upward to between 87.5% and 99.2%. Discrepancies between performance measures based on EHRs automated review alone and those based on automated review plus manual review were due to two types of misclassification: failure to correctly identify performance of quality measures among true, eligible patients; and failure to correctly identify reasons for exception for patients. The rate of misclassification from both sources of error ranged from 33% (angiotensin converting enzyme [ACE] inhibitor/angiotensin receptor blockers [ARB] measure) to 81% (antiplatelet therapy measure) for the individual measures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Cardio-HIT study is currently ongoing, testing the coronary artery disease measures in 5 physician practices, having 5 different EHRs in use for at least 5 years. As part of the project, the integrated measure specifications were translated to data fields within the practice EHR. Final results from this project are expected to be available soon. The results regarding exception rate reporting will be analyzed to determine if any changes to the measures are required. Review of the preliminary data suggests that the work group might consider incorporating the types of exceptions most frequently reported as explicit examples to aid in implementation and to clarify instances in which the particular treatment/therapy might not be appropriate. In addition, the work group may want to revisit the need for a system reason exclusion in the pharmacotherapy measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2007 PQRI submission data, Iowa Foundation for Medical Care. [internet]. [accessed 2012 Apr 09]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association, Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement®. Chronic stable coronary artery disease performance measurement set. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2011 Jan. 95 p.  [75 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;DOQ and DOQ-IT measure specifications. [internet]. [accessed 2009 Mar 12]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Electronic Health Records (EHR) Demonstration: Demonstration summary. [internet]. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services; [accessed 2012 Apr 09]. [19]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;IFMC report to The Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement, Chronic Stable Artery Disease Measurement Set Report of Pilot Testing, 2001. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Medicare Physician Group Practice Demonstration. [internet]. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services; 2011 Jul&amp;nbsp;[accessed 2012 Apr 09]. [9]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Persell SD, Wright JM, Thompson JA, Kmetik KS, Baker DW. Assessing the validity of national quality measures for coronary artery disease using an electronic health record. Arch Intern Med. 2006 Nov 13;166(20):2272-7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17101947&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Preliminary Cardio-HIT project data, provided by American Medical Association. [Not for distribution or publication]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Current routine use" /></Field><Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use"><Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Ambulatory/Office-based Care" /></Field><Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Individual Clinicians or Public Health Professionals" /></Field><Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Unspecified" /></Field><Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 18 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Either male or female" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care"><Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Person- and Family-centered Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories"><Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Getting Better" /><FieldValue Value="Living with Illness" /></Field><Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" /><FieldValue Value="Equity" /><FieldValue Value="Patient-centeredness" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure"><Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;12 months&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" /></Field><Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" /><FieldValue Value="Encounter" /><FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" /></Field><Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;All patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of coronary artery disease seen within a 12 month period&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: See the original measure documentation for administrative codes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Patients for whom there are documented results of an evaluation of level of activity AND an evaluation of presence or absence of anginal symptoms* in the medical record &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: See the original measure documentation for administrative codes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*Evaluation of level of activity and evaluation of presence or absence of anginal symptoms should include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Documentation of Canadian Cardiovascular Society (CCS) Angina Class (see below) OR &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Completion of a disease-specific questionnaire (e.g., Seattle Angina Questionnaire or other validated questionnaire) to quantify angina and level of activity &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;Canadian Cardiovascular Society (CCS) Angina Classification&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Class 0: Asymptomatic &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Class 1: Angina with strenuous exercise &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Class 2: Angina with moderate exertion &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Class 3: Angina with mild exertion&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Walking 1-2 level blocks at normal pace &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Climbing 1 flight of stairs at normal pace &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Class 4: Angina at any level of physical exertion &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Fixed time period or point in time" /></Field><Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" /><FieldValue Value="Electronic health/medical record" /><FieldValue Value="Paper medical record" /></Field><Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" /></Field><Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" /></Field><Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information"><Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Measure #3: symptom &amp;amp; activity assessment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="The Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&amp;#174; Measurement Sets" /></Field><Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="Chronic Stable Coronary Artery Disease Performance Measurement Set" /></Field><Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="American Medical Association on behalf of the American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association, and Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® - Clinical Specialty Collaboration" /></Field><Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p"><FieldValue Value="American College of Cardiology Foundation - Medical Specialty Society" /><FieldValue Value="American Heart Association - Medical Specialty Society" /><FieldValue Value="Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® - Clinical Specialty Collaboration" /></Field><Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joseph Drozda, MD, FACC (&lt;em&gt;Co-Chair&lt;/em&gt;) (Cardiology; Methodology); Joseph V. Messer, MD, MACC, FAHA (&lt;em&gt;Co-Chair&lt;/em&gt;) (Cardiology); John Spertus, MD, FACC, FAHA (&lt;em&gt;Co-Chair&lt;/em&gt;) (Cardiology); Bruce Abramowitz, MD, FACC (Interventional Cardiology; Measure Implementation); Karen Alexander, MD, FACC (Cardiology; Geriatrics); Craig T. Beam, CRE (Patient Representative); Robert O. Bonow, MD, MACC, FAHA, FACP (Cardiology); Jill S. Burkiewicz, PharmD, BCPS (Pharmacy); Michael Crouch, MD, MSPH (Family Medicine); David C. Goff, Jr., MD, PhD, FAHA, FACP (Internal Medicine); Richard Hellman, MD, FACP, FACE (Endocrinology); Thomas James, III, FACP, FAAP (Health Plan Representative); Marjorie L. King, MD, FACC, MAACVPR (Cardiology; Cardiac Rehabilitation); Edison A. Machado, Jr., MD, MBA (Measure Implementation); Eduardo Ortiz, MD, MPH (Internal Medicine; Guideline Development); Michael O'Toole, MD, FACC (Cardiology; Electrophysiology; Measure Implementation); Stephen D. Persell, MD, MPH (Internal Medicine; Measure Implementation); Jesse M. Pines, MD, MBA, MSCE, FAAEM (Emergency Medicine); Frank J. Rybicki, MD, PhD (Radiology); Lawrence B. Sadwin (Patient Representative); Joanna D. Sikkema, MSN, ANP-BC, FAHA (Cardiology); Peter K. Smith, MD (Thoracic Surgery); Patrick J. Torcson, MD, FACP, MMM (Hospital Medicine); John B. Wong, MD, FACP (Internal Medicine)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American College of Cardiology Foundation&lt;/em&gt;: Jensen S. Chiu, MHA; Kay Conley, RN, MSN, BC; Charlene L. May; Melanie Shahriary, RN, BSN&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Heart Association&lt;/em&gt;: Anne Leonard, MPH, RN, CCRC, FAHA; Mark D. Stewart, MPH; Gayle Whitman, PhD, RN&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Medical Association&lt;/em&gt;: Mark Antman, DDS, MBA; Heidi Bossley, MSN, MBA; Christopher Carlucci, MBA; Kerri Fei, MSN, RN; Bridget Gulotta, MSN; Kendra Hanley, MS; Karen Kmetik, PhD; Samantha Tierney, MPH; Chyna Wilcoxson; Temaka Williams, MPH, MBA; Greg Wozniak, PhD&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;National Committee for Quality Assurance Liaison&lt;/em&gt;: Manasi Tirodkar, PhD, MS&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Joint Commission Liaison&lt;/em&gt;: Millie J. Perich, MS, RN&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conflicts, if any, are disclosed in accordance with the Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&amp;reg; conflict of interest policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date"><FieldValue Value="2011 Jan" /></Field><Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coding/Specifications updates occur annually. The Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement (PCPI) has a formal measurement review process that stipulates regular (usually on a three-year cycle, when feasible) review of the measures. The process can also be activated if there is a major change in scientific evidence, results from testing or other issues are noted that materially affect the integrity of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2014 Jan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates a previous version: American College of Cardiology, American Heart Association, Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&amp;reg;. Clinical performance measures: chronic stable coronary artery disease. Tools developed by physicians for physicians. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2005. 8 p.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The individual measure, &quot;Measure #3: Symptom &amp;amp; Activity Assessment,&quot; is published in the &quot;Chronic Stable Coronary Artery Disease Performance Measurement Set.&quot; This document and technical specifications are available in Portable Document Format (PDF) from the American Medical Association (AMA)-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&amp;reg; Web site: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ama-assn.org/ama/pub/physician-resources/physician-consortium-performance-improvement.page&quot; title=&quot;AMA/PCPI Web site&quot;&gt;www.physicianconsortium.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For further information, please contact AMA staff by e-mail at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cqi@ama-assn.org&quot;&gt;cqi@ama-assn.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI on September 26, 2003. The information was verified by the measure developer on January 28, 2004. This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI on September 28, 2005. This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on May 11, 2011. This NQMC summary was updated again by ECRI Institute on April 4, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;copy; 2010 American College of Cardiology, American Heart Association and American Medical Association. All Rights Reserved. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CPT&amp;reg; Copyright 2009 American Medical Association &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production"><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association, Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement®. Chronic stable coronary artery disease performance measurement set. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association (AMA); 2011 Jan. 95 p.  [75 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer"><Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the NQMC Inclusion Criteria which may be found at &lt;a href=&quot;../about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.qualitymeasures.ahrq.gov/about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" /></Field></Section></Version>
