<Version><xmlsource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlsource><Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General"><Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Cardiovascular disease: the percentage of patients with a new diagnosis of hypertension aged 30 or over and who have not attained the age of 75, recorded between the preceding 1 April to 31 March (excluding those with pre-existing CHD, diabetes, stroke and/or TIA) who have a recorded CVD risk assessment score (using an assessment tool agreed with the NHS CB) of greater than or equal to 20% in the preceding 12 months who are currently treated with statins.&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;British Medical Association (BMA) and NHS Employers. 2014/15 general medical services (GMS) contract quality and outcomes framework (QOF): guidance for GMS contract 2014/15. London (UK): British Medical Association, National Health Service Confederation; 2014 Mar. 182 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field Name ="UMLS Concepts"><FieldValue Value="ICD9CM: Cardiovascular disease, unspecified  (429.2); Complications affecting other specified body systems, not elsewhere classified, hypertension  (997.91)"/><FieldValue Value="MSH: Cardiovascular Diseases ; Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors ; Hypertension ; Primary Prevention ; Risk Assessment "/><FieldValue Value="MTH: Cardiovascular Diseases ; Framingham coronary heart disease 10 year risk score (assessment) ; Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors ; Hypertensive disease ; Risk Assessment "/><FieldValue Value="SNOMEDCT_US: Assessment for risk of cardiovascular disease ; Disorder of cardiovascular system ; Framingham coronary heart disease 10 year risk score ; Framingham coronary heart disease 5 year risk score ; HMG-CoA reductase inhibitor ; Hypertensive disorder ; Primary prevention ; Primary prevention of cardiovascular disease ; QRISK cardiovascular disease risk score ; Risk assessment ; Vascular disease risk assessment "/></Field></Section><Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain"><Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Process" /></Field><Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract"><Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the percentage of patients with a new diagnosis of hypertension aged 30 or over and who have not attained the age of 75, recorded between the preceding 1 April to 31 March (excluding those with pre-existing coronary heart disease [CHD], diabetes, stroke and/or transient ischaemic attack [TIA]) who have a recorded cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk assessment score (using an assessment tool agreed with the National Health Service Commissioning Board [NHS CB]) of greater than or equal to 20% in the preceding 12 months who are currently treated with statins. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cardiovascular disease (CVD) is the most common cause of death in the United Kingdom (UK) and importantly for patients, the major cause of premature death (before the age of 65). Moreover, of greater significance for the National Health Service (NHS), CVD is not the commonest cause of disability (through stroke and heart failure [HF] particularly) and hospital admission. This results in CVD being the major cost driver for health utilisation and remains the end point disease for many other chronic disorders, especially diabetes and renal disease.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Primary prevention works and evidence-based interventions can dramatically reduce risk. This was evidenced in North Karelia when CVD mortality was reduced by 50 per cent through rigid implementation of public health and individual patient interventions. Analysis of coronary heart disease (CHD) trends in Ireland found that over a 15 year period, primary prevention achieved a two-fold larger reduction in CHD deaths than secondary prevention, where 68 per cent of the 2,530 fewer deaths attributable to CHD (using the IMPACT CHD mortality model) having occurred in patients without recognised CHD compared to 32 per cent in CHD patients.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For primary prevention of CVD, people at risk need to be identified before CVD has become established. To assess risk in those likely to be at high-risk (for example, people with hypertension) a validated assessment tool is needed that evaluates a range of modifiable and non-modifiable risk factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) clinical guideline on lipid modification (National Collaborating Centre for Primary Care, 2008) recommends statin therapy for the primary prevention of CVD for adults who have an estimated 20 per cent or greater 10-year risk of developing CVD. A number of risk assessment tools can be used to estimate cardiovascular risk for this Quality and Outcomes Framework (QOF) indicator. These include: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Framingham &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Joint British Society 2 (JBS2) &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;QRISK &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The three assessment tools listed above allow a structured risk assessment to be undertaken. However, each has a different age threshold; so to include the use of all three tools, the age range for this indicator has been set at aged 30 or over and under the age of 75. Contractors will be expected to use one of the three tools to assess their patients. If the tool normally available on the contractor's clinical system is not age appropriate, one of the other tools may be used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Framingham (Anderson et al., 1991) and JBS2 (British Cardiac Society [BCS] et al., 2005) are based on the American Framingham equations. These equations are of limited use in the UK because they were developed in a historic United States population. The equations overestimate risk by up to 50 per cent in most contemporary northern European populations, particularly for people living in more affluent areas and underestimate risk in higher risk populations, such as people who are the most socially deprived. Framingham makes no allowance for a family history of premature CHD and does not take account of ethnicity, but does have a full data set.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The newer risk score QRISK has the advantage of including other variables, such as measures of social deprivation, ethnicity and family history. QRISK uses data from UK general practice databases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Framingham and JBS2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;The variables needed to estimate risk using the Framingham tool are age, sex, systolic blood pressure (mean of two previous systolic readings), total cholesterol, high density lipoprotein cholesterol, smoking status and presence of left ventricular hypertrophy. JBS2 uses the Framingham variables with the exception of the presence of left ventricular hypertrophy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Framingham is an assessment of actual, not estimated, risk. The values used should have been recorded no longer than six months before the date of the risk assessment and before any treatment for hypertension. Framingham is not suitable for patients with pre-existing CVD (CHD, angina, stroke, transient ischaemic attack [TIA] or peripheral artery disease [PAD]), diabetes, chronic kidney disease (CKD) (if the patient has an estimated glomerular filtration rate [eGFR] below 60) or familial hypercholesterolemia, or in patients already taking lipid-lowering medication before a new diagnosis of hypertension.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Framingham risk score may be used in patients aged 35 or over and under the age of 75. JBS2 may be used in people aged 40 or over.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QRISK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;The QRISK CVD risk calculator was developed by doctors and academics working in the NHS and is based on routinely collected data from general practitioners (GPs) across the country. The current version of QRISK is QRISK2 (Hippisley-Cox et al., 2008; QRISK 2-2013, 2014). QRISK2 uses the following variables to calculate CVD risk: self-assigned ethnicity, age, sex, smoking status, systolic blood pressure, total cholesterol, high-density lipoprotein (HDL) cholesterol, body mass index (BMI), family history of CHD in a first degree relative younger than 60, Townsend deprivation score, treated hypertension, type 2 diabetes, renal disease, atrial fibrillation (AF) and rheumatoid arthritis (RA). QRISK2 may be used in patients aged 30 or over and under the age of 85.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clinical Effectiveness of Primary Prevention&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;For people without clinical evidence of CVD, statin therapy is associated with a reduction of fatal and nonfatal myocardial infarction (MI) and the composite outcome CHD death or nonfatal MI, fatal and nonfatal stroke and revascularisation. In trials predominantly comprising primary prevention but including a minority of people with established CVD, meta-analysis found that statin therapy was associated with a reduction in the risk of all-cause mortality, fatal and nonfatal MI and the composite outcomes of CHD death, nonfatal MI, fatal or nonfatal stroke and coronary revascularisation. For primary prevention lower intensity statins are safe and cost-effective. It is recommended that treatment for the primary prevention of CVD in patients with hypertension be initiated with simvastatin 40 mg. If there are potential drug interactions, or simvastatin 40 mg is contraindicated, a lower dose or alternative statin preparation may be chosen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The NICE clinical guideline on lipid modification makes recommendations on how a 10-year CVD risk score of 20 per cent or greater should be managed. It also makes recommendations on communication between practitioners and patients about CVD risk assessment and treatment. These include the following: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Setting aside adequate time during the consultation to provide information on risk assessment and to allow any questions to be answered. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Documenting the discussion relating to the consultation on risk assessment and the patient's decision. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Offering information about the person's absolute risk* of CVD and about the absolute benefits and harms of an intervention over a 10-year period. This information:&#xA;    &lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Presents individualised risk and benefit scenarios &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Presents the absolute risk of events numerically &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Uses appropriate diagrams and text &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The guideline also recommends that if the patient's CVD risk is considered to be at a level that merits intervention but they decline the offer of treatment, they are advised that their CVD risk should be considered again in the future. The guideline also notes that CVD risk may be underestimated in people who are already taking anti-hypertensive or lipid modification therapy, or who have recently stopped smoking. It recommends that clinical judgement be used in such cases to decide on further treatment of risk factors in people who are below the 20 per cent CVD risk threshold.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For patients with hypertension, the guideline recommends that before they are offered lipid modification therapy for primary prevention, all other modifiable CVD risk factors are considered and their management optimised if possible. Baseline blood tests and clinical assessment are to be performed and co-morbidities and secondary causes of dyslipidaemia treated. Assessment includes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Smoking status &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Alcohol consumption &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;BMI or other measures of obesity (see the NICE clinical guideline on obesity [National Collaborating Centre for Primary Care, 2006]) &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Fasting total cholesterol, low-density lipoprotein (LDL) cholesterol, HDL cholesterol and triglycerides (if fasting levels are not already available) &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Fasting blood glucose &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Renal function &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Liver function (transaminases) &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Thyroid stimulating hormone (TSH) if dyslipidaemia is present &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The NICE guideline on lipid modification also recommends that the decision whether to initiate statin therapy is made after an informed discussion between the responsible clinician and the person about the risks and benefits of statin treatment, taking into account additional factors such as co-morbidities and life expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The guideline also states that a target for total or LDL cholesterol is not recommended for people who are treated with a statin for primary prevention of CVD and that once a person has been started on a statin for primary prevention, repeat lipid measurement is unnecessary. It is recommended that clinical judgement and patient preference should guide the review of drug therapy and whether to review the lipid profile.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npci.org.uk&quot; title=&quot;National Prescribing Centre Web site&quot;&gt;www.npci.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; for more information about explaining risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Anderson KM, Odell PM, Wilson PW, Kannel WB. Cardiovascular disease risk profiles. Am Heart J. 1991 Jan;121(1 Pt 2):293-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=1985385&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;British Cardiac Society, British Hypertension Society, Diabetes UK, HEART UK, Primary Care Cardiovascular Society, Stroke Association. JBS 2: Joint British Societies' guidelines on prevention of cardiovascular disease in clinical practice. Heart. 2005 Dec;91 Suppl 5:v1-52. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=16365341&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;British Medical Association (BMA) and NHS Employers. 2014/15 general medical services (GMS) contract quality and outcomes framework (QOF): guidance for GMS contract 2014/15. London (UK): British Medical Association, National Health Service Confederation; 2014 Mar. 182 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hippisley-Cox J, Coupland C, Vinogradova Y, Robson J, Minhas R, Sheikh A, Brindle P. Predicting cardiovascular risk in England and Wales: prospective derivation and validation of QRISK2. BMJ. 2008 Jun 28;336(7659):1475-82. [60 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18573856&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Collaborating Centre for Primary Care. Lipid modification. Cardiovascular risk assessment and the modification of blood lipids for the primary and secondary prevention of cardiovascular disease. London (UK): National Institute for Health and Clinical Excellence (NICE); 2008 May. 37 p.&amp;nbsp;(Clinical guideline; no. 67).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Collaborating Centre for Primary Care. Obesity: the prevention, identification, assessment and management of overweight and obesity in adults and children. London (UK): National Institute for Health and Clinical Excellence; 2006 Dec. 2590 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;QRISK 2-2013 risk calculator. [Web site]. ClinRisk, Ltd.; 2013.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cardiovascular disease (CVD); primary prevention; hypertension; risk assessment; statins&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients with a new diagnosis of hypertension aged 30 or over and who have not attained the age of 75, recorded between the preceding 1 April to 31 March (excluding those with pre-existing coronary heart disease [CHD], diabetes, stroke and/or transient ischaemic attack [TIA]), who have a recorded cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk assessment score (using an assessment tool agreed with the National Health Service Commissioning Board [NHS CB]) of greater than or equal to 20% in the preceding 12 months (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of patients from the denominator who are currently treated with statins&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure"><Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" /><FieldValue Value="A formal consensus procedure, involving experts in relevant clinical, methodological,  public health and organizational sciences" /><FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" /></Field><Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Current routine use" /></Field><Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use"><Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Ambulatory/Office-based Care" /></Field><Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Practice or Public Health Sites" /></Field><Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Unspecified" /></Field><Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age 30 to 74 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Either male or female" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care"><Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories"><Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Living with Illness" /></Field><Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure"><Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 April to 31 March of the preceding year&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" /></Field><Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" /><FieldValue Value="Diagnostic Evaluation" /><FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" /></Field><Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Patients with a new diagnosis of hypertension aged 30 or over and who have not attained the age of 75, recorded between the preceding 1 April to 31 March (excluding those with pre-existing coronary heart disease [CHD], diabetes, stroke and/or transient ischaemic attack [TIA]), who have a recorded cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk assessment score (using an assessment tool agreed with the National Health Service Commissioning Board [NHS CB]) of greater than or equal to 20% in the preceding 12 months &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Patients with the following conditions are excluded from this indicator:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;CHD or angina &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Stroke or TIA &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Peripheral vascular disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Familial hypercholesterolaemia &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Diabetes &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Chronic kidney disease (CKD) with an estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) below 30 &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Exception reporting applies to indicators in any domain of the Quality and Outcomes Framework (QOF), where the achievement is determined by the percentage of patients receiving the specified level of care.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&quot;Exceptions&quot; relate to registered patients who are on the relevant disease register or in the target population group and would ordinarily be included in the indicator denominator, but who are excepted by the contractor on the basis of one or more of the exception criteria. Patients are removed from the denominator and numerator for an indicator if they have been both excepted and they have not received the care specified in the indicator wording. If the patient has been excepted but subsequently the care has been carried out within the relevant time period, the patient will be included in both the denominator and the numerator (achievement will always override an exception).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;Patients may be excepted if they fall within the strict criteria detailed below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: upper-alpha;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients who have been recorded as refusing to attend review who have been invited on at least three occasions during the financial year to which the achievement payments relate (except in the case of indicator CS002, where the patient should have been invited on at least three occasions during the period of time specified in the indicator during which achievement is to be measured [e.g., the preceding five years ending on 31 March in the financial year to which achievement payments relate]). &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients for whom it is not appropriate to review the chronic disease parameters due to particular circumstances, for example, a patient who has a terminal illness or is extremely frail. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients newly diagnosed or who have recently registered with the contractor who should have measurements made within three months and delivery of clinical standards within nine months, e.g., blood pressure or cholesterol measurements within target levels. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients who are on maximum tolerated doses of medication whose levels remain sub-optimal. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients for whom prescribing a medication is not clinically appropriate, e.g., those who have an allergy, contraindication or have experienced an adverse reaction. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Where a patient has not tolerated medication. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Where a patient does not agree to investigation or treatment (informed dissent) and this has been recorded in their patient record following a discussion with the patient. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Where the patient has a supervening condition which makes treatment of their condition inappropriate, e.g., cholesterol reduction where the patient has liver disease. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Where an investigative service or secondary care service is unavailable. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;Refer to the original measure documentation for further details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Number of patients from the denominator who are currently treated with statins &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Fixed time period or point in time" /></Field><Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Electronic health/medical record" /><FieldValue Value="Paper medical record" /></Field><Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" /></Field><Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" /></Field><Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="71" OrdBy="570" ID="613" Name="Prescriptive Standard" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Achievement thresholds: 40% to 90%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="9" OrdBy="580" ID="614" Name="Evidence for Prescriptive Standard" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;British Medical Association (BMA) and NHS Employers. 2014/15 general medical services (GMS) contract quality and outcomes framework (QOF): guidance for GMS contract 2014/15. London (UK): British Medical Association, National Health Service Confederation; 2014 Mar. 182 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information"><Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;CVD-PP001. In those patients with a new diagnosis of hypertension aged 30 or over and who have not attained the age of 75, recorded between the preceding 1 April to 31 March (excluding those with pre-existing CHD, diabetes, stroke and/or TIA), who have a recorded CVD risk assessment score (using an assessment tool agreed with the NHS CB) of &amp;ge;20% in the preceding 12 months, who are currently treated with statins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="Quality and Outcomes Framework Indicators" /></Field><Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="Cardiovascular Disease - Primary Prevention (CVD-PP)" /></Field><Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="British Medical Association - Medical Specialty Society" /><FieldValue Value="National Health Service (NHS) Confederation - National Government Agency [Non-U.S.]" /></Field><Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p"><FieldValue Value="British Medical Association - Medical Specialty Society" /><FieldValue Value="National Health Service (NHS) Confederation - National Government Agency [Non-U.S.]" /></Field><Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The expert panel who developed the indicators were funded by the English Department of Health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main indicator development group is based in the National Primary Care Research and Development Centre in the University of Manchester. They are: Professor Helen Lester, NPCRDC, MB, BCH, MD; Dr. Stephen Campbell, NPCRDC, PhD; Dr. Umesh Chauhan, NPCRDC, MB, BS, PhD.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Others involved in the development of individual indicators are: Professor Richard Hobbs, Dr. Richard McManus, Professor Jonathan Mant, Dr. Graham Martin, Professor Richard Baker, Dr. Keri Thomas, Professor Tony Kendrick, Professor Brendan Delaney, Professor Simon De Lusignan, Dr. Jonathan Graffy, Dr. Henry Smithson, Professor Sue Wilson, Professor Claire Goodman, Dr. Terry O'Neill, Dr. Philippa Matthews, Dr. Simon Griffin, Professor Eileen Kaner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None for the main indicator development group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="82" OrdBy="700" ID="626" Name="Endorser" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="National Health Service - National Government Agency [Non-U.S.]" /></Field><Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date"><FieldValue Value="2014 Mar" /></Field><Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates a previous version: British Medical Association (BMA) and NHS Employers. Quality and outcomes framework guidance for GMS contract 2013/14. London (UK): British Medical Association, National Health Service Confederation; 2013 Mar. 203 p. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The individual measure, &quot;CVD-PP001. In Those Patients with a New Diagnosis of Hypertension Aged 30 or Over and Who Have Not Attained the Age of 75, Recorded Between the Preceding 1 April to 31 March (Excluding Those with Pre-existing CHD, Diabetes, Stroke and/or TIA), Who Have a Recorded CVD Risk Assessment Score (Using an Assessment Tool Agreed with the NHS CB) of &amp;ge;20% in the Preceding 12 Months, Who Are Currently Treated with Statins,&quot; is published in the &quot;2014/15 General Medical Services (GMS) Contract Quality and Outcomes Framework (QOF): Guidance for GMS Contract 2014/15.&quot; This document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bma.org.uk/-/media/files/pdfs/practical%20advice%20at%20work/contracts/gpqofguidance2014-15.pdf&quot; title=&quot;BMA Web site&quot;&gt;British Medical Association Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on September 25, 2009. The information was verified by the measure developer on March 4, 2010. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on June 21, 2011. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on August 27, 2012, November 26, 2013 and again on October 1, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;No copyright restrictions apply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production"><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;British Medical Association (BMA) and NHS Employers. 2014/15 general medical services (GMS) contract quality and outcomes framework (QOF): guidance for GMS contract 2014/15. London (UK): British Medical Association, National Health Service Confederation; 2014 Mar. 182 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer"><Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the NQMC Inclusion Criteria which may be found at &lt;a href=&quot;../about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.qualitymeasures.ahrq.gov/about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" /></Field></Section></Version>
