<Version><xmlsource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlsource><Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General"><Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Acute myocardial infarction (AMI): median time from hospital arrival to primary PCI in AMI patients with ST-segment elevation or LBBB on the ECG performed closest to hospital arrival time.&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 4.3b. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; 2014 Apr. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field Name ="UMLS Concepts"><FieldValue Value="ICD9CM: Acute myocardial infarction of unspecified site, episode of care unspecified  (410.90); Bundle branch block, unspecified  (426.50); Electrocardiogram  (89.52)"/><FieldValue Value="MSH: Angioplasty, Balloon, Coronary ; Bundle-Branch Block ; Electrocardiography ; Hospitalization ; Myocardial Infarction ; Patient Admission ; Percutaneous Coronary Intervention ; Time Factors "/><FieldValue Value="MTH: Acute myocardial infarction ; Angioplasty, Balloon, Coronary ; Bundle-Branch Block ; Electrocardiogram ; Electrocardiography ; Hospitalization ; Left Bundle-Branch Block ; Myocardial Infarction ; Percutaneous Coronary Intervention ; ST segment elevation (finding) "/><FieldValue Value="SNOMEDCT_US: Acute myocardial infarction ; Bundle branch block ; Electrocardiographic procedure ; Inpatient care ; Left bundle branch block ; Myocardial infarction ; Percutaneous coronary intervention ; ST segment elevation "/><FieldValue Value="UMD: Physiologic Monitor Modules, Electrocardiography  (20-771)"/></Field></Section><Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain"><Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Process" /></Field><Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract"><Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the median time from hospital arrival to primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) in acute myocardial infarction (AMI) patients 18 years of age and older with ST-segment elevation or left bundle branch block (LBBB) on the electrocardiogram (ECG) performed closest to hospital arrival time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure rate should be analyzed in conjunction with the measure rate for the related measure, &lt;a href=&quot;/content.aspx?id=48085&quot; title=&quot;Measure Summary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Acute myocardial infarction (AMI): percent of patients with ST-segment elevation or LBBB on the ECG closest to arrival time receiving primary PCI during the hospital stay with a time from hospital arrival to PCI of 90 minutes or less&lt;/a&gt;. These measures, used together, will assist in understanding the median time to primary PCI, and will identify the number of AMI patients that are receiving primary PCI within 90 minutes of hospital arrival and potential opportunities for improvement to decrease the median time to primary PCI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The early use of primary angioplasty in patients with ST-segment myocardial infarction (STEMI) results in a significant reduction in mortality and morbidity. The earlier primary coronary intervention is provided, the more effective it is (Brodie et al., 1998; DeLuca et al., 2004). National guidelines recommend the prompt initiation of percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) in patients presenting with ST-elevation myocardial infarction (American College of Emergency Physicians&amp;nbsp;et al., 2013; Kushner et al., 2009).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Emergency Physicians, Society for Cardiovascular Angiography and Interventions, O'Gara PT, Kushner FG, Ascheim DD, Casey DE, Chung MK, de Lemos JA, Ettinger SM, Fang JC, Fesmire FM, Franklin BA, Granger CB, Krumholz HM, Linderbaum JA, Morrow DA, Newby LK, Ornato JP, Ou N, Radford MJ, Tamis-Holland JE, Tommaso CL, Tracy CM, Woo YJ, Zhao DX, Anderson JL, Jacobs AK, Halperin JL, Albert NM, Brindis RG, Creager MA, DeMets D, Guyton RA, Hochman JS, Kovacs RJ, Kushner FG, Ohman EM, Stevenson WG, Yancy CW. 2013 ACCF/AHA guideline for the management of ST-elevation myocardial infarction: executive summary: a report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2013 Jan 29;61(4):485-510. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=23256913&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Brodie BR, Stuckey TD, Wall TC, Kissling G, Hansen CJ, Muncy DB, Weintraub RA, Kelly TA. Importance of time to reperfusion for 30-day and late survival and recovery of left ventricular function after primary angioplasty for acute myocardial infarction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1998 Nov;32(5):1312-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=9809941&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;DeLuca G, Suryapranata H, Ottervanger JP, Antman EM. Time delay to treatment and mortality in primary angioplasty for acute myocardial infarction: every minute of delay counts. Circulation. 2004 Mar 16;109(10):1223-5. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15007008&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kushner FG, Hand M, Smith SC Jr, King SB 3rd, Anderson JL, Antman EM, Bailey SR, Bates ER, Blankenship JC, Casey DE Jr, Green LA, Hochman JS, Jacobs AK, Krumholz HM, Morrison DA, Ornato JP, Pearle DL, Peterson ED, Sloan MA, Whitlow PL, Williams DO. 2009 focused updates: ACC/AHA guidelines for the management of patients with ST-elevation myocardial infarction (updating the 2004 guideline and 2007. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009 Dec 1;54(23):2205-41. [163 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19942100&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 4.3b. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; 2014 Apr. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acute myocardial infarction (AMI); ST-segment elevation; left bundle branch block (LBBB); electrocardiogram (ECG); primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acute myocardial infarction (AMI) patients 18 years of age and older with ST-segment elevation or left bundle branch block (LBBB) on the electrocardiogram (ECG) performed closest to hospital arrival who received primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) within 24 hours after hospital arrival (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Continuous variable statement&lt;/em&gt;: Time (in minutes) from hospital arrival to primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) in patients with ST-segment elevation or left bundle branch block (LBBB) on the electrocardiogram (ECG) performed closest to hospital arrival&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure"><Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" /><FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" /></Field><Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each year, an estimated 620,000 Americans will have a new coronary event, and approximately 295,000 will have a recurrent event. An estimated additional 150,000 silent first myocardial infarctions occur each year. Approximately every 34 seconds, an American will have a coronary event, and approximately every 1 minute 23 seconds, one will die. In 2004, acute myocardial infarction (AMI) resulted in 695,000 hospital stays and $31 billion in health expenditures. The risk of further cardiovascular complications, including recurrent MI, sudden cardiac death, heart failure, stroke, and angina pectoris, among AMI survivors is substantial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Go AS, Mozaffarian D, Roger VL, Benjamin EJ, Berry JD, Blaha MJ, Dai S, Ford ES, Fox CS, Franco S, Fullerton HJ, Gillespie C, Hailpern SM, Heit JA, Howard VJ, Huffman MD, Judd SE, Kissela BM, Kittner SJ, Lackland DT, Lichtman JH, Lisabeth LD, Mackey RH, Magid DJ, Marcus GM, Marelli A, Matchar DB, McGuire DK, Mohler ER, Moy CS, Mussolino ME, Neumar RW, Nichol G, Pandey DK, Paynter NP, Reeves MJ, Sorlie PD, Stein J, Towfighi A, Turan TN, Virani SS, Wong ND, Woo D, Turner MB, American Heart Association Statistics Committee and Stroke Statistics Subcommittee. Heart disease and stroke statistics--2014 update: a report from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2014 Jan 21;129(3):e28-292. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=24352519&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core measure pilot project was a collaboration among The Joint Commission, five state hospital associations, five measurement systems, and 83 hospitals from across nine states. Participating hospitals collected and reported data for acute myocardial infarction (AMI) measures from December 2000 to December 2001.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Core measure reliability visits were completed in the summer of 2001 at a random sample of 16 participating hospitals across 6 states.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Preliminary data from the pilot project show an average median rate of 310.85 minutes (5.2 hours) for time to percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty (PTCA), indicating an opportunity for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure is reviewed semi-annually and revised as needed to ensure reliable specifications. An independent abstracting contractor is utilized by the Hospital Inpatient Quality Reporting Program to monitor validity of the measure specifications. Feedback from this contractor is incorporated into the proposed changes for each manual update.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Telligen, Hospital Inpatient Quality Reporting Program Support Contractor. Hospital Inpatient Quality Reporting (IQR) Program overview. [internet]. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); [accessed 2014 Jul 16]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Joint Commission. A comprehensive review of development and testing for national implementation of hospital core measures. Oakbrook Terrace (IL): The Joint Commission; 40 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="37" OrdBy="200" ID="579" Name="National Guideline Clearinghouse Link" Type="xref"><FieldValue Value="&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guideline.gov/content.aspx?id=39429&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2013 ACCF/AHA guideline for the management of ST-elevation myocardial infarction. A report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines.&lt;/a&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Current routine use" /></Field><Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use"><Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient" /></Field><Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" /></Field><Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Specified" /></Field><Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 18 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Either male or female" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care"><Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories"><Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Getting Better" /></Field><Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" /><FieldValue Value="Timeliness" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure"><Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discharges January 1 through December 31&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" /></Field><Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" /><FieldValue Value="Diagnostic Evaluation" /><FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" /><FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" /><FieldValue Value="Therapeutic Intervention" /></Field><Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Discharges 18 years of age and older with an &lt;em&gt;International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-9-CM) Principal Diagnosis Code&lt;/em&gt; for acute myocardial infarction (AMI) &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;ICD-9-CM Principal and Other Procedure Codes&lt;/em&gt; for percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) (as defined in the appendices of the original measure documentation) &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; ST-segment elevation or left bundle branch block (LBBB) on the electrocardiogram (ECG) performed closest to hospital arrival &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; primary PCI performed within 24 hours after hospital arrival&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients less than 18 years of age &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients who have a Length of Stay (LOS) greater than 120 days &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients enrolled in clinical trials &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients received as a transfer from an inpatient or outpatient department of another hospital &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients received as a transfer from the emergency/observation department of another hospital &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients received as a transfer from an ambulatory surgery center &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients administered fibrinolytic agent prior to PCI &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;PCI described as non-primary by a physician/advanced practice nurse/physician assistant (physician/APN/PA) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients who did not receive PCI within 90 minutes and had a documented &lt;em&gt;Reason for Delay in PCI&lt;/em&gt; (as defined in the Data Dictionary) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Continuous variable statement&lt;/em&gt;: Time (in minutes) from hospital arrival to primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) in patients with ST-segment elevation or left bundle branch block (LBBB) on the electrocardiogram (ECG) performed closest to hospital arrival&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" /></Field><Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" /><FieldValue Value="Electronic health/medical record" /><FieldValue Value="Paper medical record" /></Field><Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Acute Myocardial Infarction (AMI) Initial Patient Population Algorithm Flowchart&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AMI-8: Median Time to Primary PCI Flowchart&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Mean/Median" /></Field><Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Desired value is a lower score" /></Field><Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="71" OrdBy="570" ID="613" Name="Prescriptive Standard" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;National guidelines recommend that a percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) be performed within 90 minutes of hospital arrival in patients with ST-elevation myocardial infarction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="9" OrdBy="580" ID="614" Name="Evidence for Prescriptive Standard" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Emergency Physicians, Society for Cardiovascular Angiography and Interventions, O'Gara PT, Kushner FG, Ascheim DD, Casey DE, Chung MK, de Lemos JA, Ettinger SM, Fang JC, Fesmire FM, Franklin BA, Granger CB, Krumholz HM, Linderbaum JA, Morrow DA, Newby LK, Ornato JP, Ou N, Radford MJ, Tamis-Holland JE, Tommaso CL, Tracy CM, Woo YJ, Zhao DX, Anderson JL, Jacobs AK, Halperin JL, Albert NM, Brindis RG, Creager MA, DeMets D, Guyton RA, Hochman JS, Kovacs RJ, Kushner FG, Ohman EM, Stevenson WG, Yancy CW. 2013 ACCF/AHA guideline for the management of ST-elevation myocardial infarction: executive summary: a report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2013 Jan 29;61(4):485-510. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=23256913&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information"><Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;AMI-8: median time to primary PCI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures" /></Field><Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="Acute Myocardial Infarction" /></Field><Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" /><FieldValue Value="The Joint Commission - Health Care Accreditation Organization" /></Field><Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p"><FieldValue Value="Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services/The Joint Commission - None" /></Field><Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All external funding for measure development has been received and used in full compliance with The Joint Commission's Corporate Sponsorship policies, which are available upon written request to The Joint Commission.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) funding is from the United States Government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure grew from Cooperative Cardiovascular Project (CCP) work. The Joint Commission co-developed this measure. The original versions of this measure have undergone revisions over the years, and have evolved into the current version which exists in the &quot;Specifications Manual for National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures&quot; today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Expert panel members have made full disclosure of relevant financial and conflict of interest information in accordance with the Conflict of Interest policies, copies of which are available upon written request to The Joint Commission and the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date"><FieldValue Value="2014 Apr" /></Field><Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is reviewed and updated by the developing organizations every 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2015 Jan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates a previous version: Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 4.2b. Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; 2013 Jan. various p. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The individual measure, &quot;AMI-8: Median Time to Primary PCI,&quot; is published in &quot;Specifications Manual for National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures.&quot; This document is available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jointcommission.org/specifications_manual_for_national_hospital_inpatient_quality_measures.aspx&quot; title=&quot;The Joint Commission Web site&quot;&gt;The Joint Commission Web site&lt;/a&gt;. Information is also available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic/Page/QnetTier2&amp;amp;cid=1141662756099&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;QualityNet Web site&lt;/a&gt;. Check The Joint Commission Web site and QualityNet Web site regularly for the most recent version of the specifications manual and for the applicable dates of discharge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="15" OrdBy="790" ID="635" Name="Companion Documents" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A software application designed for the collection and analysis of quality improvement data, the CMS Abstraction and Reporting Tool (CART), is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic/Page/QnetTier2&amp;amp;cid=1138900279093&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;QualityNet Web site&lt;/a&gt;. Supporting documentation is also available. For more information, e-mail CMS PROINQUIRIES at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:proinquiries@cms.hhs.gov&quot;&gt;proinquiries@cms.hhs.gov&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The Joint Commission. A comprehensive review of development and testing for national implementation of hospital core measures. Oakbrook Terrace (IL): The Joint Commission; 40 p. This document is available in Portable Document Format (PDF) from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jointcommission.org/assets/1/18/A_Comprehensive_Review_of_Development_for_Core_Measures.pdf&quot; title=&quot;The Joint Commission Web site&quot;&gt;The Joint Commission Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The Joint Commission. Attributes of core performance measures and associated evaluation criteria. Oakbrook Terrace (IL): The Joint Commission; 5 p. This document is available in PDF from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jointcommission.org/assets/1/18/Attributes_of_Core_Performance_Measures_and_Associated_Evaluation_Criteria.pdf&quot; title=&quot;The Joint Commission Web site&quot;&gt;The Joint Commission Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was originally completed by ECRI on February 7, 2003. This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on October 6, 2005, April 16, 2007, and October 26, 2007.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Joint Commission informed NQMC that this measure was updated on August 13, 2008 and provided an updated version of the NQMC summary. This NQMC summary was updated accordingly by ECRI Institute on November 11, 2008. The information was verified by the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) on January 22, 2009.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Joint Commission informed NQMC that this measure was updated on October 1, 2009 and provided an updated version of the NQMC summary. This NQMC summary was updated accordingly by ECRI Institute on November 25, 2009. The information was verified by CMS on February 18, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on October 8, 2010. The information was verified by The Joint Commission on December 3, 2010. The information was verified by CMS on January 6, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on May 13, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Joint Commission informed NQMC that this measure was updated on March 28, 2012 and provided an updated version of the NQMC summary. This NQMC summary was updated accordingly by ECRI Institute on July 10, 2012. The information was verified by CMS on August 1, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Joint Commission and CMS informed NQMC that this measure was updated on June 10, 2013 and provided an updated version of the NQMC summary. This NQMC summary was updated accordingly by ECRI Institute on January 31, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Joint Commission and CMS informed NQMC that this measure was updated again on August 29, 2014 and provided an updated version of the NQMC summary. This NQMC summary was updated accordingly by ECRI Institute on September 24, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Specifications Manual for National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures [Version 4.3b, April, 2014] is the collaborative work of the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services and The Joint Commission. The Specifications Manual is periodically updated by the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services and The Joint Commission. Users of the Specifications Manual for National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures should periodically verify that the most up-to-date version is being utilized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production"><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 4.3b. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; 2014 Apr. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer"><Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the NQMC Inclusion Criteria which may be found at &lt;a href=&quot;../about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.qualitymeasures.ahrq.gov/about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" /></Field></Section></Version>
