<Version><xmlsource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlsource><Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General"><Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Heart failure (HF): hospital 30-day, all-cause, unplanned risk-standardized readmission rate (RSRR) following HF hospitalization.&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 4.2b. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; 2013 Jan. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field Name ="UMLS Concepts"><FieldValue Value="ICD9CM: Heart failure, unspecified  (428.9)"/><FieldValue Value="MSH: Heart Failure ; Hospitalization ; Patient Readmission ; Risk Assessment ; Time Factors "/><FieldValue Value="MTH: Heart failure ; Hospitalization ; Risk Assessment "/><FieldValue Value="SNOMEDCT_US: Heart failure ; Inpatient care ; Risk assessment "/></Field></Section><Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain"><Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Outcome" /></Field><Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract"><Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure* estimates a hospital-level risk-standardized all-cause unplanned 30-day readmission for patients discharged from the hospital with a principal discharge diagnosis of heart failure (HF).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*This is a Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) only measure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) developed the heart failure (HF) 30-day readmission measure to complement the existing HF process-of-care and mortality measures. Risk-standardized readmission rates (RSRRs) can provide important additional information about quality of care that is currently not captured by the process and mortality measures and is currently unavailable to hospitals. Variation in readmission, after adjusting for case-mix, may reflect differences in hospitals' general environments (such as coordination of care, patient safety policies, and staffing) or variation in care processes not measured in the current core measure set. Outcome measures can focus attention on a broader set of healthcare activities that affect patients' well-being. Moreover, improving outcomes is the ultimate goal of quality improvement, and thus the inclusion of outcomes measures assists in attaining improvement goals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readmission of patients who were recently discharged after hospitalization with HF represents an important, expensive, and often preventable adverse outcome. The risk of readmission can be modified by the quality and type of care provided to these patients. Improving readmission rates is the joint responsibility of hospitals and clinicians. Measuring readmission will create incentives to invest in interventions to improve hospital care, better assess the readiness of patients for discharge, and facilitate transitions to outpatient status. This measure is also responsive to the call by the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC) to develop readmission measures, with HF highlighted as one of seven conditions that account for nearly 30% of potentially preventable readmissions in the 15-day window after initial hospital discharge (MedPAC, 2007).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Krumholz H, Normand SL, Keenan P, et al, Drye E, Bhat K, Wang Y, Ross J, Schuur J, Stauffer B, Bernheim S, Epstein A, Herrin J, Federer J, Mattera J, Wang Y, Mulvey G, Schreiner G. Hospital 30-day heart failure readmission measure methodology: report prepared for the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services. Englewood (CO): Colorado Foundation for Medical Care (CFMC); 2008 Apr 23. 53 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC). Report to congress: promoting greater efficiency in Medicare. Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC); 2007. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 4.2b. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; 2013 Jan. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heart failure (HF); 30-day readmission rate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The measure cohort consists of admissions for Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) and Veterans Health Administration (VA) beneficiaries aged 65 years and older discharged from non-federal acute care hospitals or VA hospitals with a principal discharge diagnosis of heart failure (HF).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The risk-standardized readmission rate (RSRR) is calculated as the ratio of the number of &quot;predicted&quot; readmissions to the number of &quot;expected&quot; readmissions, multiplied by the national unadjusted readmission rate. The &quot;denominator&quot; is the number of readmissions expected on the basis of the nation's performance with that hospital's case-mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the measure cohort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1219069855841&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2013 Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level 30-day Risk-Standardized Readmission Measures for Acute Myocardial Infarction, Heart Failure, and Pneumonia&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The measure assesses unplanned readmissions to any acute care hospital within a 30-day period from the date of discharge from the index heart failure (HF) admission.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hospital-specific risk-standardized readmission rate (RSRR) is calculated as the ratio of the number of &quot;predicted&quot; readmissions to the number of &quot;expected&quot; readmissions, multiplied by the national unadjusted readmission rate. The &quot;numerator&quot; of the ratio is the number of readmissions within 30 days predicted on the basis of the hospital's performance with its observed case-mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1219069855841&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2013 Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level 30-day Risk-Standardized Readmission Measures for Acute Myocardial Infarction, Heart Failure, and Pneumonia&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure"><Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" /></Field><Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Heart failure (HF) is the most common principal hospital discharge diagnosis among Medicare beneficiaries, and is among the most expensive conditions billed to Medicare (Andrews and Elixhauser, 2007). Readmission rates following discharge for HF are high. All-cause 30-day readmission rates per thousand patients discharged with HF increased by 11 percent between 1992 and 2001 (Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services [CMS]/Medicare Quality Monitoring System [MQMS], 2006). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Readmission rates are influenced by the quality of inpatient and outpatient care, the availability and use of effective disease management programs, and the bed capacity of the local health care system. Some of the variation in readmissions may be attributable to delivery system characteristics (Fisher et al., 1994). Also, interventions during and after a hospitalization can be effective in reducing readmission rates in geriatric populations generally (Benbassat and Taragin, 2000; Naylor et al., 1999; Coleman et al., 2006) and for elderly HF patients specifically (Phillips et al., 2004; Naylor et al., 2004; Koelling, 2005; Krumholz et al., 2002; Nohria et al., 2002; Rich et al., 1995). Moreover, such interventions can be cost saving (Coleman et al., 2006; Naylor et al., 1999; Krumholz et al., 2002; Naylor et al., 2004; Rich et al., 1995; Koelling, 2005; Phillips et al., 2004). Tracking readmissions also emphasizes improvement in care transitions and care coordination. Although discharge planning is required by Medicare as a condition of participation for hospitals, transitional care focuses more broadly on &quot;hand-offs&quot; of care from one setting to another, and may have implications for quality and costs (Coleman, 2005). Despite positive results in disease management studies, many post-hospital HF management programs have been discontinued, most often due to financial considerations (Seow et al., 2006). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC) has called for hospital-specific public reporting of readmission rates, identifying HF as one of seven conditions that account for nearly 30% of potentially preventable readmissions in the 15-day window after initial hospital discharge (MedPAC, 2007). MedPAC finds that readmissions are common, costly, and often preventable. Based on 2005 Medicare data, MedPAC estimates that about 12.5% of Medicare HF admissions were followed by a potentially preventable readmission within 15 days, accounting for more than 90,000 admissions at a cost of $590 million. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Andrews RM, Elixhauser A. The national hospital bill: growth trends and 2005 update on the most expensive conditions by payer. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2007 Dec. &amp;nbsp;(HCUP statistical brief; no. 42).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Benbassat J, Taragin M. Hospital readmissions as a measure of quality of health care: advantages and limitations. Arch Intern Med. 2000 Apr 24;160(8):1074-81. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=10789599&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS). Medicare quality monitoring system (MQMS). Available at: http://www.cms.hhs.gov/QualityInitiativesGenInfo/15_MQMS.asp. [internet]. 2006.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Coleman EA, Parry C, Chalmers S, Min SJ. The care transitions intervention: results of a randomized controlled trial. Arch Intern Med. 2006 Sep 25;166(17):1822-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17000937&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Coleman EA. Background paper on transitional care performance measurement. Appendix I. In: Institute of Medicine, performance measurement: accelerating improvement. Washington (DC): National Academy Press; 2005. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Fisher ES, Wennberg JE, Stukel TA, Sharp SM. Hospital readmission rates for cohorts of Medicare beneficiaries in Boston and New Haven. N Engl J Med. 1994 Oct 13;331(15):989-95. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=8084356&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Koelling TM. Multifaceted outpatient support can improve outcomes for people with heart failure. Commentary. Evid Based Cardiovasc Med. 2005 Jun;9(2):138-41. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=16380013&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Krumholz HM, Amatruda J, Smith GL, Mattera JA, Roumanis SA, Radford MJ, Crombie P, Vaccarino V. Randomized trial of an education and support intervention to prevent readmission  of patients with heart failure. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2002 Jan 2;39(1):83-9. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=11755291&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC). Report to congress: promoting greater efficiency in Medicare. Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MedPAC); 2007. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Naylor MD, Brooten D, Campbell R, Jacobsen BS, Mezey MD, Pauly MV, Schwartz JS. Comprehensive discharge planning and home follow-up of hospitalized elders: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 1999 Feb 17;281(7):613-20. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=10029122&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Naylor MD, Brooten DA, Campbell RL, Maislin G, McCauley KM, Schwartz JS. Transitional care of older adults hospitalized with heart failure: a randomized,  controlled trial. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2004 May;52(5):675-84. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15086645&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Nohria A, Lewis E, Stevenson LW. Medical management of advanced heart failure. JAMA. 2002 Feb 6;287(5):628-40. [99 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=11829703&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Phillips CO, Wright SM, Kern DE, Singa RM, Shepperd S, Rubin HR. Comprehensive discharge planning with postdischarge support for older patients with congestive heart failure: a meta-analysis. JAMA. 2004 Mar 17;291(11):1358-67. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15026403&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rich MW, Beckham V, Wittenberg C, Leven CL, Freedland KE, Carney RM. A multidisciplinary intervention to prevent the readmission of elderly patients with congestive heart failure. N Engl J Med. 1995;333(18):1190-5. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=7565975&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Seow H, Phillips CO, Rich MW, Spertus JA, Krumholz HM, Lynn J. Isolation of health services research from practice and policy: the example of chronic heart failure management. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2006 Mar;54(3):535-40. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=16551325&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each year, we evaluate the performance of the models. Over the most recent three-year time period, model performance was stable; the area under the ROC curve (c-statistic) remained constant at 0.61.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to &quot;2013 Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level 30-day Risk-Standardized Readmission Measures for Acute Myocardial Infarction, Heart Failure, and Pneumonia&quot; for additional information (see also the &quot;Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2013 measures updates and specifications report: hospital-level 30-day risk-standardized readmission measures for acute myocardial infarction, heart failure, and pneumonia (version 6.0). Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2013 Mar. 67 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Current routine use" /></Field><Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use"><Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient" /></Field><Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" /></Field><Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 65 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Either male or female" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care"><Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories"><Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Getting Better" /></Field><Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure"><Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discharges July 1, 2009 through June 30, 2012&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" /></Field><Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" /><FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" /><FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" /></Field><Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;The target population for this measure includes admissions for Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) and Veterans Health Administration (VA) beneficiaries aged greater than or equal to 65 years discharged from non-federal acute care hospitals or VA hospitals with a principal discharge diagnosis of heart failure (HF)*.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) FFS beneficiaries with an index hospitalization within a non-federal acute care hospital are included if they have been enrolled in Part A and Part B Medicare for the 12 months prior to the date of admission to ensure a full year of administrative data for risk adjustment. (This requirement is dropped for patients with an index admission within a VA hospital.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-9-CM) codes that define the patient cohort:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;402.01: Hypertensive heart disease, malignant, with heart failure &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;402.11: Hypertensive heart disease, benign, with heart failure &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;402.91: Hypertensive heart disease, unspecified, with heart failure &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;404.01: Hypertensive heart and chronic kidney disease, malignant, with heart failure and with chronic kidney disease stage I through stage IV, or unspecified &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;404.03: Hypertensive heart and chronic kidney disease, malignant, with heart failure and with chronic kidney disease stage V or end stage renal disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;404.11: Hypertensive heart and chronic kidney disease, benign, with heart failure and with chronic kidney disease stage I through stage IV, or unspecified &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;404.13: Hypertensive heart and chronic kidney disease, benign, with heart failure and chronic kidney disease stage V or end stage renal disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;404.91: Hypertensive heart and chronic kidney disease, unspecified, with heart failure and with chronic kidney disease stage I through stage IV, or unspecified &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;404.93: Hypertensive heart and chronic kidney disease, unspecified, with heart failure and chronic kidney disease stage V or end stage renal disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.0: Congestive heart failure, unspecified&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.1: Left heart failure&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.20: Systolic heart failure, unspecified&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.21: Systolic heart failure, acute&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.22: Systolic heart failure, chronic&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.23: Systolic heart failure, acute or chronic&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.30: Diastolic heart failure, unspecified&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.31: Diastolic heart failure, acute&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.32: Diastolic heart failure, chronic&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.33: Diastolic heart failure, acute or chronic&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.40: Combined systolic and diastolic heart failure, unspecified&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.41: Combined systolic and diastolic heart failure, acute&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.42: Combined systolic and diastolic heart failure, chronic&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.43: Combined systolic and diastolic heart failure, acute or chronic &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;428.9: Heart failure, unspecified &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Admissions for patients with an in-hospital death are excluded because they are not eligible for readmission. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Admissions for patients without at least 30 days post-discharge enrollment in FFS Medicare are excluded because the 30-day readmission outcome cannot be assessed in this group. This exclusion applies only to patients who have index admissions in non-VA hospitals. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Admissions for patients having a principal diagnosis of HF during the index hospitalization and subsequently transferred to another acute care facility are excluded because we are focusing on discharges to non-acute care settings. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Admissions for patients who are discharged against medical advice (AMA) are excluded because providers did not have the opportunity to deliver full care and prepare the patient for discharge. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;The measure assesses unplanned readmissions to any acute care hospital within a 30-day period from the date of discharge from the index heart failure (HF) admission.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hospital-specific risk-standardized readmission rate (RSRR) is calculated as the ratio of the number of &quot;predicted&quot; readmissions to the number of &quot;expected&quot; readmissions, multiplied by the national unadjusted readmission rate. The &quot;numerator&quot; of the ratio is the number of readmissions within 30 days predicted on the basis of the hospital's performance with its observed case-mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1219069855841&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2013 Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level 30-day Risk-Standardized Readmission Measures for Acute Myocardial Infarction, Heart Failure, and Pneumonia&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Admissions identified as planned by the planned readmissions algorithm are not counted as readmissions. The &quot;algorithm&quot; is a set of criteria for classifying readmissions as planned using Medicare claims. The algorithm identifies admissions that are typically planned and may occur within 30 days of discharge from the hospital. The Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) based the planned readmission algorithm on three principles: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A few specific, limited types of care are always considered planned (obstetrical delivery, transplant surgery, maintenance chemotherapy, rehabilitation); &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Otherwise, a planned readmission is defined as a non-acute readmission for a scheduled procedure; and &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Admissions for acute illness or for complications of care are never planned &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The planned readmission algorithm uses a flow chart and four tables of procedures and conditions to operationalize these principles and to classify readmissions as planned. The flow chart and tables are available in a report, &lt;em&gt;CMS Planned Readmission Algorithm Version 2.1&lt;/em&gt;, available at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cms.gov/Medicare/Quality-Initiatives-Patient-Assessment-Instruments/HospitalQualityInits/Measure-Methodology.html&quot; title=&quot;CMS Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CMS Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" /></Field><Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" /></Field><Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Adverse Health State" /></Field><Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" /></Field><Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Desired value is a lower score" /></Field><Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3069" OrdBy="550" ID="611" Name="Description of Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our approach to risk adjustment was tailored to and appropriate for a publicly reported outcome measure, as articulated in the American Heart Association (AHA) Scientific Statement &quot;Standards for Statistical Models Used for Public Reporting of Health Outcomes&quot; (Krumholz et al., 2006).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The measures adjust for key variables that are clinically relevant and have strong relationships with the outcome (e.g., age, sex, comorbid diseases, and indicators of frailty). For each patient, covariates are obtained from administrative data extending 12 months prior to, and including, the index admission. For all patients, information from Medicare inpatient claims, physician Part B claims and hospital outpatient claims are used for risk adjustment. For patients with an index admission in a Veterans Health Administration (VA) hospital, VA administrative data is also obtained. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The VA administrative data includes 41 diagnosis and 46 procedure codes (as opposed to 25 and 25, respectively, in Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services [CMS] administrative data). For the index hospitalization, all diagnosis and procedure codes were retained. For risk adjustment, all diagnosis and procedure codes were retained for visits prior to the index hospitalization. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The models seek to adjust for case differences based on the clinical status of the patient at the time of the index admission. Accordingly, only comorbidities that convey information about the patient at that time or in the 12 months prior, and not complications that arise during the course of the index hospitalization are included in the risk adjustment. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The final set of risk-adjustment variables included:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; summary=&quot;Final Set of Risk-adjustment Variables&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;Demographics&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Age 65 (years above 65, continuous) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Male &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;Cardiovascular&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;History of coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) surgery &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Cardio-respiratory failure and shock &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Congestive heart failure &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Acute coronary syndrome &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Chronic atherosclerosis or angina &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Valvular and rheumatic heart disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Specified arrhythmias &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Vascular or circulatory disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Other and unspecified heart disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;Comorbidity&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Metastatic cancer or acute leukemia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Cancer &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Diabetes mellitus (DM) or DM complications &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Protein-calorie malnutrition &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Disorders of fluid, electrolyte, acid-base &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Liver and biliary disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Peptic ulcer, hemorrhage, other specified gastrointestinal disorders &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Other gastrointestinal disorders &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Severe hematological disorders &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Iron deficiency or other anemias and blood disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Dementia or other specified brain disorders &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Drug/alcohol abuse/dependence/psychosis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Major psychiatric disorders &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Depression &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Other psychiatric disorders &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Hemiplegia, paraplegia, paralysis, functional disability &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Stroke &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Fibrosis of lung and other chronic lung disorders &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Asthma &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;End-stage renal disease or dialysis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Renal failure &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Nephritis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Other urinary tract disorders &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Decubitus ulcer or chronic skin ulcer &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hierarchical logistic regression modeling is used to calculate a hospital-specific risk-standardized readmission rate (RSRR). This approach is analogous to a ratio of &quot;observed&quot; to &quot;expected&quot; used in other types of statistical analyses. It conceptually allows for a comparison of a particular hospital's performance given its case-mix to an average hospital's performance with the same case-mix. Thus, a lower ratio indicates lower-than-expected readmission or better quality, and a higher ratio indicates higher-than-expected readmission or worse quality. To assess hospital performance in any reporting period, the model coefficients are re-estimated using the years of data in that period. Refer to &quot;2013 Measures Updates and Specifications Report: Hospital-level 30-day Risk-Standardized Readmission Measures for Acute Myocardial Infarction, Heart Failure, and Pneumonia&quot; for additional information (see also the &quot;Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full details of the development of the risk-standardization model for this measure are available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;www.qualitynet.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information"><Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;READM-30-HF: hospital 30-day all-cause risk standardized readmission rate (RSRR) following heart failure (HF) hospitalization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures" /></Field><Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="CMS Readmission Measures" /></Field><Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services/The Joint Commission - None" /></Field><Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p"><FieldValue Value="Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" /><FieldValue Value="Yale-New Haven Health Services Corporation/Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation under contract to Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Academic Affiliated Research Institute" /></Field><Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was developed by a team of clinical and statistical experts from Yale University/Yale-New Haven Hospital Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (Yale-CORE) and Harvard University, through a Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) contract with the Colorado Foundation for Medicare Care (CFMC).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="82" OrdBy="700" ID="626" Name="Endorser" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="National Quality Forum - None" /></Field><Field FieldID="3091" OrdBy="705" ID="696" Name="NQF Number" Type="plain-text"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3510" OrdBy="710" ID="627" Name="Date of Endorsement" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2013 Jan 31&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3083" OrdBy="720" ID="628" Name="Measure Initiative(s)" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Hospital Compare" /></Field><Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date"><FieldValue Value="2013 Jan" /></Field><Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note&lt;/strong&gt;: This measure has been updated. The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse is working to update this summary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The individual measure, &quot;READM-30-HF: Hospital 30-day All-cause Risk Standardized Readmission Rate (RSRR) Following Heart Failure (HF) Hospitalization,&quot; is published in &quot;Specifications Manual for National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures.&quot; An update of this document is available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jointcommission.org/specifications_manual_for_national_hospital_inpatient_quality_measures.aspx&quot; title=&quot;The Joint Commission Web site&quot;&gt;The Joint Commission Web site&lt;/a&gt;. Information is also available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic/Page/QnetTier2&amp;amp;cid=1141662756099&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;QualityNet Web site&lt;/a&gt;. Check The Joint Commission Web site and QualityNet Web site regularly for the most recent version of the specifications manual and for the applicable dates of discharge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="15" OrdBy="790" ID="635" Name="Companion Documents" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2013 measures updates and specifications report: hospital-level 30-day risk-standardized readmission measures for acute myocardial infarction, heart failure, and pneumonia (version 6.0). Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2013 Mar. 67 p. This document is available in Portable Document Format (PDF) from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic%2FPage%2FQnetTier4&amp;amp;cid=1219069855841&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;QualityNet Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Hospital compare: a quality tool provided by Medicare. [internet]. Washington (DC): U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; [accessed 2013 May 23]. This is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hospitalcompare.hhs.gov/&quot; title=&quot;Medicare Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Medicare Web site&lt;/a&gt;. See the related &lt;a href=&quot;https://innovations.ahrq.gov/qualitytools/hospital-compare&quot; title=&quot;QualityTools&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;QualityTools&lt;/a&gt; summary. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research &amp;amp; Evaluation (CORE). Medicare hospital quality chartbook. Performance report on outcome measures. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2013 Sep. 86 p. This document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cms.gov/Medicare/Quality-Initiatives-Patient-Assessment-Instruments/HospitalQualityInits/Downloads/-Medicare-Hospital-Quality-Chartbook-2013.pdf&quot; title=&quot;CMS Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CMS Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research &amp;amp; Evaluation (CORE). Planned readmission algorithm. Version 2.1. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2013 Mar. 35 p. This document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cms.gov/Medicare/Quality-Initiatives-Patient-Assessment-Instruments/HospitalQualityInits/Measure-Methodology.html&quot; title=&quot;CMS Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CMS Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on June 23, 2009. The information was verified by the measure developer on December 29, 2009.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on November 8, 2010. The information was verified by the measure developer on December 17, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on May 18, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on August 23, 2012. The information was verified by the measure developer on October 19, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated again by ECRI Institute on December 4, 2013. The information was verified by the measure developer on January 10, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Specifications Manual for National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures [Version 4.2b, January, 2013] is the collaborative work of the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services and The Joint Commission. The Specifications Manual is periodically updated by the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services and The Joint Commission. Users of the Specifications Manual for National Hospital Quality Measures should periodically verify that the most up-to-date version is being utilized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production"><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 4.2b. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; 2013 Jan. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer"><Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the NQMC Inclusion Criteria which may be found at &lt;a href=&quot;../about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.qualitymeasures.ahrq.gov/about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" /></Field></Section></Version>
