<Version><xmlsource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlsource><Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General"><Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Heart failure (HF): hospital 30-day, all-cause, risk-standardized mortality rate (RSMR) following HF hospitalization.&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 4.2b. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; 2013 Jan. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field Name ="UMLS Concepts"><FieldValue Value="ICD9CM: Heart failure, unspecified  (428.9)"/><FieldValue Value="MSH: Heart Failure ; Hospital Mortality ; Mortality ; Risk Assessment ; Time Factors "/><FieldValue Value="MTH: Heart failure ; Mortality Vital Statistics ; Risk Assessment "/><FieldValue Value="SNOMEDCT_US: Heart failure ; Mortality rate ; Risk assessment "/></Field></Section><Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain"><Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Outcome" /></Field><Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract"><Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure* estimates a hospital-level risk-standardized mortality rate (RSMR) for patients discharged from the hospital with a principal diagnosis of heart failure (HF).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*This is a Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) only measure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heart failure (HF) is the leading cause of hospitalization among Medicare beneficiaries and is associated with considerable risk of morbidity and mortality. Although HF is a progressive illness for which death may be an inevitable consequence rather than a marker of poor quality, clinical experience suggests that the care for these patients is highly variable and studies suggest gaps in quality of hospital care, particularly in the transition to outpatient care. Moreover, there is substantial inter-hospital variation in the risk of death at 30 days that is not explained by differences in case-mix. Many stakeholders, including patient organizations, are interested in outcomes measures for this common condition that could be used to assess the relative performance of a hospital and provide the opportunity for comparison with other institutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 4.2b. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; 2013 Jan. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heart failure (HF); 30-day mortality rate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The measure cohort consists of admissions for Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) and Veterans Health Administration (VA) beneficiaries aged 65 years and older discharged from non-federal acute care hospitals or VA hospitals, having a principal discharge diagnosis of heart failure (HF).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hospital-specific risk-standardized mortality rate (RSMR) is calculated as the ratio of the number of &quot;predicted&quot; deaths to the number of &quot;expected&quot; deaths, multiplied by the national unadjusted mortality rate. The &quot;denominator&quot; is the number of deaths expected on the basis of the nation's performance with that hospital's case-mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the measure cohort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic/Page/QnetTier3&amp;amp;cid=1163010421830&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2013 Measures Updates and Specifications: Acute Myocardial Infarction, Heart Failure, and Pneumonia 30-Day Risk-Standardized Mortality Measures&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The measure counts death from any cause within 30 days after the index admission date.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hospital-specific risk-standardized mortality rate (RSMR) is calculated as the ratio of the number of &quot;predicted&quot; deaths to the number of &quot;expected&quot; deaths, multiplied by the national unadjusted mortality rate. The &quot;numerator&quot; of the ratio is the number of deaths within 30 days predicted on the basis of the hospital's performance with its observed case-mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic/Page/QnetTier3&amp;amp;cid=1163010421830&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2013 Measures Updates and Specifications: Acute Myocardial Infarction, Heart Failure, and Pneumonia 30-Day Risk-Standardized Mortality Measures&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure"><Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" /></Field><Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The prevalence of heart failure (HF) in the United States (U.S.) is high, with 5.2 million Americans currently diagnosed with this condition (Rosamond et al., 2007). HF incidence increases with age and approaches 10 per 1000 population after age 65 (Rosamond et al., 2007). HF is one of the most common causes for hospital admissions among Medicare beneficiaries (Merrill and Elixhauser, 2005) and hospital discharges for HF increased 175% from 1979 to 2004 (Rosamond et al., 2007). A recent study reported that more than 2.5 million Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) beneficiaries were hospitalized for HF during 2001-2005, and more than 1 in 10 Medicare beneficiaries died within 30 days of hospitalization (Curtis et al., 2008). Thirty-day HF mortality rates vary considerably across hospitals (Rosenthal et al., 2000) and hospitals that perform well on the Hospital Quality Alliance (HQA) performance measures have lower risk-adjusted mortality rates (Jha et al., 2007). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The high prevalence and considerable morbidity and mortality associated with HF create an economic burden on the healthcare system. In 2005, HF was the fifth most expensive condition treated in U.S. hospitals, accounting for 3.5% of the national hospital bill. It was also the second most expensive condition billed to Medicare that year, accounting for 5.5% of Medicare's hospital bill (Andrews and Elixhauser, 2007). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Many current hospital interventions are known to decrease the risk of death within 30 days of hospital admission. Current process-based performance measures, however, cannot capture all the ways that care within the hospital might influence outcomes. As a result, many stakeholders, including patient organizations, are interested in outcomes measures that would permit groups of providers to assess their relative outcomes performance for the purpose of internal quality improvement or public reporting. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Mortality of patients with&amp;nbsp;HF represents a significant outcome potentially related to quality of care. This rate-based indicator identifies an undesirable outcome of care. High rates warrant investigation into the quality of care provided. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Andrews RM, Elixhauser A. The national hospital bill: growth trends and 2005 update on the most expensive conditions by payer. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2007 Dec. &amp;nbsp;(HCUP statistical brief; no. 42).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Curtis LH, Greiner MA, Hammill BG, Kramer JM, Whellan DJ, Schulman KA, Hernandez AF. Early and long-term outcomes of heart failure in elderly persons, 2001-2005. Arch Intern Med. 2008 Dec 8;168(22):2481-8. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19064833&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Jha AK, Orav EJ, Li Z, Epstein AM. The inverse relationship between mortality rates and performance in the Hospital  Quality Alliance measures. Health Aff (Millwood). 2007 Jul-Aug;26(4):1104-10. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17630453&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Merrill CT, Elixhauser A. Hospitalization in the United States, 2002: HCUP fact book no. 6. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2005. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rosamond W, Flegal K, Friday G, Furie K, Go A, Greenlund K, Haase N, Ho M, Howard V, Kissela B, Kittner S, Lloyd-Jones D, McDermott M, Meigs J, Moy C, Nichol G, O'donnell CJ, Roger V, Rumsfeld J, Sorlie P, Steinberger J, Thom T, Wasserthiel-Smoller S, Hong Y. Heart Disease and Stroke Statistics--2007 Update. A Report From the American Heart Association Statistics Committee and Stroke Statistics Subcommittee. Circulation. 2007 Feb 6;115(5):e69-171. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=17194875&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rosenthal GE, Baker DW, Norris DG, Way LE, Harper DL, Snow RJ. Relationships between in-hospital and 30-day standardized hospital mortality: implications for profiling hospitals. Health Serv Res. 2000 Mar;34(7):1449-68. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=10737447&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hospital-specific risk-standardized mortality estimates derived from this claims-based model were compared to hospital-specific risk-standardized mortality rates (RSMRs) based on a model developed using medical record data from the Cooperative Cardiovascular Project Initiative. The correlation coefficient of the RSMRs from the claims-based and medical record models was 0.95. Similarly, a medical record validation was conducted for use of the measures for Veterans Health Administration (VA) hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each year, we evaluate the performance of the models. Over the most recent three year period, model performance was stable; the area under the ROC curve (c-statistic) remained constant at 0.68.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to &quot;2013 Measures Updates and Specifications: Acute Myocardial Infarction, Heart Failure, and Pneumonia 30-Day Risk-Standardized Mortality Measures&quot; for additional information (see also the &quot;Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 4.2b. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; 2013 Jan. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2013 measures updates and specifications: acute myocardial infarction, heart failure, and pneumonia 30-day risk-standardized mortality measure (version 7.0). Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2013 Mar. 55 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Current routine use" /></Field><Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use"><Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Hospital Inpatient" /></Field><Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Single Health Care Delivery or Public Health Organizations" /></Field><Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 65 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Either male or female" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care"><Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Making Care Safer&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories"><Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Getting Better" /></Field><Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Safety" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure"><Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discharges July 1, 2009 through June 30, 2012&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" /></Field><Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" /><FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" /><FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" /></Field><Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;The target population for this measure includes admissions for Medicare Fee-for-Service (FFS) and Veterans Health Administration (VA) beneficiaries aged greater than or equal to 65 years discharged from non-federal acute care hospitals or VA hospitals, having a principal discharge diagnosis of heart failure (HF)*. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) FFS beneficiaries with an index hospitalization within a non-federal acute care hospital are included if they have been enrolled in Part A and Part B Medicare for the 12 months prior to the date of admission to ensure a full year of administrative data for risk-adjustment. (This requirement is dropped for patients with an index admission within a VA hospital.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For patients with more than one admission in a given year for a given condition, only one admission is randomly selected to include in the cohort (others are excluded). An index admission is the hospitalization considered for mortality outcome determination. The measure includes patients who are admitted to an acute care hospital with a diagnosis of HF and then transferred to another acute facility if the primary discharge diagnosis is HF at the second hospital. The measure considers admission to the first hospital as the start of an acute episode of care and assigns the patient's outcome to the hospital that initially admitted them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*International Classification of Diseases, Ninth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-9-CM) codes 402.01, 402.11, 402.91, 404.01, 404.03, 404.11, 404.13, 404.91, 404.93, and 428.xx. Refer to the original measure documentation for a list of all ICD-9-CM codes for HF.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;The measures exclude admissions for patients:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Who were discharged on the day of admission or the following day and did not die or get transferred (because it is less likely they had a diagnosis of HF) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;With inconsistent or unknown mortality status or other unreliable data (e.g., date of death precedes admission date) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Who were transferred from another acute care hospital or VA hospital (because the death is attributed to the hospital where the patient was initially admitted) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Enrolled in the VA or Medicare Hospice programs any time in the 12 months prior to the index hospitalization including the first day of the index admission (since it is likely these patients are continuing to seek comfort measures only) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Who were discharged against medical advice (AMA) (because providers did not have the opportunity to deliver full care and prepare the patient for discharge) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;That were not the first hospitalization in the 30 days prior to a patient's death. This exclusion criterion is applied after one admission per patient per year is randomly selected. It only applies when two randomly selected admissions occur during the transition months (July and June for data used in public reporting) and the patient subsequently dies. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;The measure counts death from any cause within 30 days after the index admission date.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hospital-specific risk-standardized mortality rate (RSMR) is calculated as the ratio of the number of &quot;predicted&quot; deaths to the number of &quot;expected&quot; deaths, multiplied by the national unadjusted mortality rate. The &quot;numerator&quot; of the ratio is the number of deaths within 30 days predicted on the basis of the hospital's performance with its observed case-mix.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This outcome measure does not have a traditional numerator and denominator like a core process measure; thus, this field is used to define the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic/Page/QnetTier3&amp;amp;cid=1163010421830&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;2013 Measures Updates and Specifications: Acute Myocardial Infarction, Heart Failure, and Pneumonia 30-Day Risk-Standardized Mortality Measures&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Institutionalization" /></Field><Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" /></Field><Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Death" /></Field><Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" /></Field><Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Desired value is a lower score" /></Field><Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3069" OrdBy="550" ID="611" Name="Description of Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our approach to risk adjustment is tailored to and appropriate for a publicly reported outcome measure, as articulated in the American Heart Association (AHA) Scientific Statement &quot;Standards for Statistical Models Used for Public Reporting of Health Outcomes&quot; (Krumholz et al., 2006).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For each patient, covariates are obtained from administrative data extending 12 months prior to, and including, the index admission. For all patients, information from Medicare inpatient claims, physician Part B claims and hospital outpatient claims are used for risk adjustment. For patients with an index admission in a Veterans Health Administration (VA) hospital, VA administrative data is also obtained. Inpatient claim records have data on hospitalization and include demographic information, principal and secondary diagnosis codes, and procedure codes. Diagnosis codes for comorbidities are also collected from physician and hospital outpatient files. These data are captured from the claim(s) for the index admission and from all inpatient and outpatient claims for the entire year before the patient's index heart failure (HF) hospitalization to be utilized in the risk-adjustment model.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The VA administrative data includes 41 diagnosis and 46 procedure codes (as opposed to 25 and 25, respectively, in Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services [CMS] administrative data). For the index hospitalization, all diagnosis and procedure codes were retained. For risk adjustment, all diagnosis and procedure codes were retained for visits prior to the index hospitalization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only variables that convey information about patients' clinical status at the time of admission are used for the risk-adjustment, while complications that arise during the course of patients' index hospitalization are not included in the model.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The final set of risk-adjustment variables included:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; summary=&quot;Final Set of Risk-adjustment Variables&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Demographics&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Age-65 (years above 65, continuous) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Male &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;Cardiovascular&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;History of percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty (PTCA) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;History of coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Congestive heart failure &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;History of acute myocardial infarction (AMI) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Other acute/subacute forms of ischemic heart disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Chronic atherosclerosis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Cardio-respiratory failure and shock &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Valvular and rheumatic heart disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;Comorbidity&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Hypertension &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Stroke &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Renal failure &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Pneumonia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Diabetes and diabetes mellitus (DM) complications &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Protein-calorie malnutrition &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Dementia and senility &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Hemiplegia, paraplegia, paralysis, functional disability &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Peripheral vascular disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Metastatic cancer, acute leukemia, and other severe cancers &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Trauma in the last year &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Major psychiatric disorders &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;                &lt;li&gt;Chronic liver disease &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hierarchical logistic regression modeling is used to calculate a hospital-specific risk-standardized mortality rate (RSMR). This approach is analogous to a ratio of &quot;observed&quot; to &quot;expected&quot; used in other types of statistical analyses. It conceptually allows for a comparison of a particular hospital's performance given its case-mix to an average hospital's performance with the same case-mix. Thus, a lower ratio indicates lower-than-expected mortality or better quality, and a higher ratio indicates higher-than-expected mortality or worse quality. To assess hospital performance in any reporting period, the model coefficients are re-estimated using the years of data in that period. Refer to &quot;2013 Measures Updates and Specifications: Acute Myocardial Infarction, Heart Failure, and Pneumonia 30-Day Risk-Standardized Mortality Measures&quot; for additional information (see also the &quot;Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full details of the development of the risk-standardization model for this measure are available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;www.qualitynet.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information"><Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;MORT-30-HF: hospital 30-day, all-cause, risk-standardized mortality rate (RSMR) following heart failure (HF) hospitalization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures" /></Field><Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="CMS Mortality Measures" /></Field><Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services/The Joint Commission - None" /></Field><Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p"><FieldValue Value="Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Federal Government Agency [U.S.]" /><FieldValue Value="Yale-New Haven Health Services Corporation/Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation under contract to Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services - Academic Affiliated Research Institute" /></Field><Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was developed by a team of clinical and statistical experts from Yale University/Yale-New Haven Hospital Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (Yale-CORE) and Harvard University, through a Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) contract with the Colorado Foundation for Medical Care (CFMC).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="82" OrdBy="700" ID="626" Name="Endorser" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="National Quality Forum - None" /></Field><Field FieldID="3091" OrdBy="705" ID="696" Name="NQF Number" Type="plain-text"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3510" OrdBy="710" ID="627" Name="Date of Endorsement" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2013 Apr 3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3083" OrdBy="720" ID="628" Name="Measure Initiative(s)" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Hospital Compare" /></Field><Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date"><FieldValue Value="2013 Jan" /></Field><Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note&lt;/strong&gt;: This measure has been updated. The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse is working to update this summary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The individual measure, &quot;MORT-30-HF: Hospital 30-day, All-cause, Risk-standardized Mortality Rate (RSMR) Following Heart Failure (HF) Hospitalization,&quot; is published in &quot;Specifications Manual for National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures.&quot; An update of this document is available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jointcommission.org/specifications_manual_for_national_hospital_inpatient_quality_measures.aspx&quot; title=&quot;The Joint Commission Web site&quot;&gt;The Joint Commission Web site&lt;/a&gt;. Information is also available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic/Page/QnetTier2&amp;amp;cid=1141662756099&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;QualityNet Web site&lt;/a&gt;. Check The Joint Commission Web site and QualityNet Web site regularly for the most recent version of the specifications manual and for the applicable dates of discharge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="15" OrdBy="790" ID="635" Name="Companion Documents" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE). 2013 measures updates and specifications: acute myocardial infarction, heart failure, and pneumonia 30-day risk-standardized mortality measure (version 7.0). Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2013 Mar. 55 p. This document is available in Portable Document Format (PDF) from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qualitynet.org/dcs/ContentServer?c=Page&amp;amp;pagename=QnetPublic/Page/QnetTier3&amp;amp;cid=1163010421830&quot; title=&quot;QualityNet Web site&quot;&gt;QualityNet Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Hospital compare: a quality tool provided by Medicare. [internet]. Washington (DC): U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; [accessed 2013 May 23]. This is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hospitalcompare.hhs.gov/&quot; title=&quot;Medicare Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Medicare Web site&lt;/a&gt;. See the related &lt;a href=&quot;https://innovations.ahrq.gov/qualitytools/hospital-compare&quot; title=&quot;QualityTools&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;QualityTools&lt;/a&gt; summary. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Yale New Haven Health Services Corporation (YNHHSC), Center for Outcomes Research &amp;amp; Evaluation (CORE). Medicare hospital quality chartbook. Performance report on outcome measures. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS); 2013 Sep. 86 p. This document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cms.gov/Medicare/Quality-Initiatives-Patient-Assessment-Instruments/HospitalQualityInits/Downloads/-Medicare-Hospital-Quality-Chartbook-2013.pdf&quot; title=&quot;CMS Web site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CMS Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on June 23, 2009. The information was verified by the measure developer on December 29, 2009.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on November 8, 2010. The information was verified by the measure developer on December 17, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was retrofitted into the new template on May 18, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on August 23, 2012. The information was verified by the measure developer on October 19, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated again by ECRI Institute on December 4, 2013. The information was verified by the measure developer on January 10, 2014. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Specifications Manual for National Hospital Inpatient Quality Measures [Version 4.2b, January, 2013] is the collaborative work of the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services and The Joint Commission. The Specifications Manual is periodically updated by the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services and The Joint Commission. Users of the Specifications Manual for National Hospital Quality Measures should periodically verify that the most up-to-date version is being utilized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production"><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Specifications manual for national hospital inpatient quality measures, version 4.2b. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), The Joint Commission; 2013 Jan. various p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer"><Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the NQMC Inclusion Criteria which may be found at &lt;a href=&quot;../about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.qualitymeasures.ahrq.gov/about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" /></Field></Section></Version>
