<Version><xmlsource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlsource><Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General"><Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Hypertension: percentage of patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of hypertension seen within a 12 month period with a blood pressure less than 140/90 mm Hg OR patients with a blood pressure greater than or equal to 140/90 mm Hg and prescribed 2 or more anti-hypertensive medications during the most recent office visit.&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association, Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement®. Hypertension performance measurement set. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association; 2011 Jan. 27 p.  [24 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field Name ="UMLS Concepts"><FieldValue Value="HCPCS: MOST RECENT DIASTOLIC BLOOD PRESSURE &lt; 90 MMHG ; MOST RECENT SYSTOLIC BLOOD PRESSURE &lt; 140 MMHG "/><FieldValue Value="ICD9CM: Complications affecting other specified body systems, not elsewhere classified, hypertension  (997.91)"/><FieldValue Value="MSH: Antihypertensive Agents ; Hypertension ; Office Visits ; Sphygmomanometers "/><FieldValue Value="MTH: Antihypertensive Agents ; Blood pressure monitoring ; Hypertensive disease "/><FieldValue Value="SNOMEDCT_US: Antihypertensive therapy ; Blood pressure monitoring ; Hypertensive disorder ; Hypotensive agent ; Sphygmomanometer "/><FieldValue Value="UMD: Sphygmomanometers  (13-106)"/></Field></Section><Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain"><Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Outcome" /></Field><Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract"><Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the percentage of patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of hypertension seen within a 12 month period with a blood pressure less than 140/90 mm Hg OR patients with a blood pressure greater than or equal to 140/90 mm Hg and prescribed 2 or more anti-hypertensive medications during the most recent office visit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Effective management of blood pressure in patients with hypertension can help prevent cardiovascular events, including myocardial infarction (MI), stroke, and the development of heart failure.*&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*The following evidence statements are quoted &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;verbatim&lt;/span&gt; from the referenced clinical guidelines:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;Classification of blood pressure for adults (JNC VII, 2004):&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table class=&quot;Note&quot; border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;thead&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;Blood Pressure Classification&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;SBP mm Hg&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;DBP mm Hg&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/thead&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;Normal&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;120&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;and &amp;lt;80&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;Prehypertension&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;120-139&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;or 80-89&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;Stage 1 Hypertension&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;140-159&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;or 90-99&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;Stage 2 Hypertension&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ge;160&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;or &amp;ge;100&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;Treating SBP and DBP to targets that are &amp;lt;140/90 mm Hg is associated with a decrease in cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk complications. In patients with hypertension and diabetes or renal disease, the BP goal is &amp;lt;130/80 mm Hg. (JNC VII, 2004)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;Therapy begins with lifestyle modification, and if BP goal is not achieved, thiazide-type diuretics should be used as initial therapy for most patients, either alone or in combination with one of the other classes (angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors [ACEIs], angiotensin receptor blockers [ARBs], beta blockers [BBs], or calcium channel blockers [CCBs]) that have also been shown to reduce one or more hypertensive complications in randomized-controlled outcome trials. Selection of one of these other agents as initial therapy is recommended when a diuretic cannot be used or a competing indication is present that requires use of a specific drug&amp;hellip;If the initial drug selected is not tolerated or contraindicated, then a drug from one of the other classes proven to reduce cardiovascular events should be substituted. (JNC VII, 2004)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Compelling Indications for Use of Individual Drug Classes for Treatment of Hypertension (JNC VII, 2004)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stable Angina and Silent Ischemia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;Unless contraindicated, pharmacologic therapy should be initiated with a BB. BBs will lower BP; reduce symptoms of angina; improve mortality; and reduce cardiac output, heart rate, and atrioventricular (AV) conduction. The reduced inotropy and heart rate decrease myocardial oxygen demand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;If angina and BP are not controlled by BB therapy alone, or if BBs are contraindicated, as in the presence of severe reactive airway disease, severe peripheral arterial disease, high-degree AV block, or the sick sinus syndrome, either long-acting dihydropyridine or nondihydropyridine CCBs may be used. CCBs decrease total peripheral resistance, which leads to reduction in BP and wall tension. CCBs also decrease coronary resistance and enhance post-stenotic coronary perfusion. Nondihyrdopyridine CCBs can decrease heart rate; when in combination with a BB however, they may cause severe bradycardia or high degrees of heart block. Therefore, long-acting dihydropyridine CCBs are preferred for combination therapy with BBs. If angina or BP is still not controlled with this two-drug regimen, nitrates can be added, but these should be used with caution in patients taking phosphodiesterase-5 inhibitors such as sildenafil. Short-acting dihydropyridine CCBs should not be used because of their potential to increase mortality, especially in the setting of acute MI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heart Failure (HF)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;HF is a &quot;compelling indication&quot; for the use of ACEI. Abundant evidence exists to justify their use with all stages of HF. In patients intolerant of ACEIs, ARBs may be used. BBs are also recommended for HF because of clinical studies demonstrating decreased morbidity and mortality, and improvement in HF symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diabetes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;Thiazide-type diuretics are beneficial in diabetics, either alone or as part of a combined regimen. Therapy with an ACEI also is an important component of most regimens to control BP in diabetic patients. ACEIs may be used alone for BP lowering but are much more effective when combined with a thiazide-type diuretic or other antihypertensive drugs. BBs, especially beta 1-selective agents, are beneficial to diabetics as part of multidrug therapy, but their value as monotherapy is less clear. A BB is indicated in a diabetic with IHD but may be less effective in preventing stroke than an ARB as was found in the LIFE study. Although BBs can cause adverse effects on glucose homeostasis in diabetics, including worsening of insulin sensitivity and potential masking of the epinephrine-mediated symptoms of hypoglycemia, these problems are usually easily managed and are not absolute contraindication for BB use. CCBs may be useful to diabetics, particularly as part of combination therapy to control BP.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronic Kidney Disease&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;The joint recommendation of the American Society of Nephrology and the National Kidney Foundation provides useful guidelines for the management of hypertensive patients with CKD. They recommend a goal BP for all CKD patients of &amp;lt;130/80 mm Hg and the need for more than one antihypertensive drug to achieve this goal. The guidelines indicate that most patients with CKD should receive an ACEI or ARB in combination with a diuretic, and many will require a loop diuretic rather than a thiazide. In addition, if there is a conflict between the goals of slowing progression of CKD and cardiovascular (CV) risk reduction, individual decision making is recommended based on risk stratification.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Asch SM, Kerr EA, Keesey J, Adams JL, Setodji CM, Malik S, McGlynn EA. Who is at greatest risk for receiving poor-quality health care. N Engl J Med. 2006 Mar 16;354(11):1147-56. [32 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=16540615&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;McGlynn EA, Asch SM, Adams J, Keesey J, Hicks J, DeCristofaro A, Kerr EA. The quality of health care delivered to adults in the United States. N Engl J Med. 2003 Jun 26;348(26):2635-45. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=12826639&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Institutes of Health, National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, National High Blood Pressure Education Program. The seventh report of the Joint National Committee on Prevention, Detection, and Treatment of High Blood Pressure. NIH Publication No. 04-5230. Bethesda (MD): National Institutes of Health; 2004 Sep. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hypertension; blood pressure (BP) control; anti-hypertensive therapy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of hypertension seen within a 12 month period (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients with a blood pressure less than 140/90 mm Hg OR patients with a blood pressure greater than or equal to 140/90 mm Hg and prescribed 2 or more anti-hypertensive medications during the most recent office visit (see the related &quot;Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure"><Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" /><FieldValue Value="One or more research studies published in a National Library of Medicine (NLM) indexed, peer-reviewed journal" /></Field><Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;According to a study analyzing the quality of care in the U.S., on average, patients with hypertension received the recommended quality of care approximately 65% of the time. Quality of care was assessed by analysis of clinician performance on 27 hypertension quality indicators. Quality of care varied significantly by indicator with average rates of adherence ranging from 21.39% for newly diagnosed patients with hypertension who had three or more measurements of blood pressure (BP) with a mean systolic blood pressure (SBP) &amp;gt;140 or a mean diastolic blood pressure (DBP) &amp;gt;90 to 76.47% for patients with a consistent average of SBP &amp;gt;140 or DBP &amp;gt;90 who had either a change in dose of anti-hypertensive regimen or repeated education regarding lifestyle modification documented. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;One in three adults in the United States has high blood pressure. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Hypertension is associated with shorter overall life expectancy, shorter life expectancy free from cardiovascular disease, and more years lived with cardiovascular disease (based on data from the Framingham Heart Study [FHS]/National Heart, Lung, &amp;amp; Blood Institute [NHLBI]). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Until 45 years of age, more men than women have high blood pressure. From 45 to 64 years of age, the percentage of men and women that have high blood pressure is similar. After age 64, the percentage of women with high blood pressure is higher than men. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Based on data from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES)/National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS), the age-adjusted prevalence of hypertension (both diagnosed and undiagnosed) in 2003-2006 was 75% for older women and 65% for older men. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;From 1988 to 1994 through 1999 to 2002, the prevalence of hypertension in adults increased from 35.8% to 41.4% among blacks, and was high among black women (44%). Prevalence among white adults also rose during this time frame from 24.3% to 28.1%. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Approximately 69% of those who have a first heart attack, 77% who have a first stroke, and 74% of those with congestive heart failure have a blood pressure greater than 140/90 mmHg (based on unpublished estimates from the NHLBI). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;From 1998 to 2000, approximately 76% of hypertensive patients with a consistent average systolic blood pressure (SBP) &amp;gt;140 or diastolic blood pressure (DBP) &amp;gt;90 over 6 months had either a change in dose in their antihypertensive regimen or repeated education regarding lifestyle modifications. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Using data from the National Ambulatory Medical Survey (NAMS), Ma and Stafford found that 39% of treated visits for hypertension were at recommended blood pressure goals.&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;There was geographic variability in the odds of being treated for hypertension (South vs. Northeast &amp;ndash;2.6) and by visit type (first time vs. return visits - 1.6). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Odds of blood pressure control were greater for patients with comorbidities (1.6). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Findings based on NHANES/NCHS data show that hypertension control rates have improved from 1999 to 2004 through 2005 to 2006. The control rates increased in both sexes, in non-Hispanic blacks, and in Mexican Americans. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The wide disparity regarding control of hypertension in the African American population is well-documented. The Jackson Heart Study (JHS) is a study of cardiovascular disease specifically in African Americans. A recently published study compared data from JHS with findings from NHANES 1999 to 2004 (adjusted to JHS parameters). Data indicate that blood pressure control rates for JHS participants was comparable to that of whites, suggesting that public health efforts to improve control have been fairly effective and that better control rates are possible in the African American population. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;From 1997 to 2007, the death rate caused by high blood pressure increased 9.0% and the actual number of deaths rose 35.6%. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In 2007, the overall death rate due to high blood pressure was 17.8. Rates differ by gender and race:&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;15.7 for white men &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;49.2 for black men &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;14.3 for white women &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;37.0 for black women &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In 2007, the number of ambulatory care visits for hypertension was 46,284,000. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The 2007 estimated direct and indirect cost of hypertension is $43.5 billion. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3502" OrdBy="170" ID="576" Name="Evidence for Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association, Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement®. Hypertension performance measurement set. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association; 2011 Jan. 27 p.  [24 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Asch SM, Kerr EA, Keesey J, Adams JL, Setodji CM, Malik S, McGlynn EA. Who is at greatest risk for receiving poor-quality health care. N Engl J Med. 2006 Mar 16;354(11):1147-56. [32 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=16540615&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ma J, Stafford RS. Screening, treatment, and control of hypertension in US private physician offices, 2003-2004. Hypertension. 2008 May;51(5):1275-81. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18347229&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Institutes of Health, National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, National High Blood Pressure Education Program. The seventh report of the Joint National Committee on Prevention, Detection, and Treatment of High Blood Pressure. NIH Publication No. 04-5230. Bethesda (MD): National Institutes of Health; 2004 Sep. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Roger VL, Go AS, Lloyd-Jones DM, Adams RJ, Berry JD, Brown TM, Carnethon MR, Dai S, de Simone G, Ford ES, Fox CS, Fullerton HJ, Gillespie C, Greenlund KJ, Hailpern SM, Heit JA, Ho PM, Howard VJ, Kissela BM, Kittner SJ, Lackland DT, Lichtman JH, Lisabeth LD, Makuc DM, Marcus GM, Marelli A, Matchar DB, McDermott MM, Meigs JB, Moy CS, Mozaffarian D, Mussolino ME, Nichol G, Paynter NP, Rosamond WD, Sorlie PD, Stafford RS, Turan TN, Turner MB, Wong ND, Wylie-Rosett J. Heart disease and stroke statistics--2011 update: a report from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2011 Feb 1;123(4):e18-209. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=21160056&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Wyatt SB, Akylbekova EL, Wofford MR, Coady SA, Walker ER, Andrew ME, Keahey WJ, Taylor HA, Jones DW. Prevalence, awareness, treatment, and control of hypertension in the Jackson Heart Study. Hypertension. 2008 Mar;51(3):650-6. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18268140&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association/Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&amp;reg; hypertension physician performance measures, in their previous specifications, have been utilized in several performance measurement projects, including the Doctor's Office Quality (DOQ) Project, the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) Physician Group Practice program, the Persell testing project, the Petersen testing project and the EQUIP Project. These projects have shown varying levels of feasibility, reliability, and performance, dependent upon the venue and modality of data collection. In addition, specific research projects have been conducted to test the reliability of these measures in various settings. Results of these testing projects have been considered and resulted in modifications to the measures, where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feasibility Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CMS Doctors' Office Quality (DOQ) Project revealed that the two hypertension measures are feasible to collect, as previously specified. As part of the DOQ project, reviewers assessed the feasibility of use of the ACC/AHA/PCPI measures in offices by performing retrospective audits of paper medical records and electronic health records.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Implementation of two of the CAD measures in the CMS Physician Group Practice program and in the EQUIP project demonstrate feasibility of these measures as specified. Additionally, the Persell and Petersen research shows that measures similar to the PCPI measures can be implemented.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The DOQ project tested inter-rater reliability twice during the project. The agreement rates for the Blood Pressure Measurement measure were 97% and 94%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3007" OrdBy="190" ID="578" Name="Evidence for Extent of Measure Testing" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association, Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement®. Hypertension performance measurement set. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association; 2011 Jan. 27 p.  [24 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, Office of Research, Development, and Information. Medicare physician group practice demonstration. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services; 2011 Jul. 9 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;DOQ and DOQ-IT measure specifications. [internet]. Baltimore (MD): Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services; [accessed 2009 Mar 12]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Persell SD, Kho AN, Thompson JA, Baker DW. Improving hypertension quality measurement using electronic health records. Med Care. 2009 Apr;47(4):388-94. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19330887&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Petersen LA, Woodard LD, Henderson LM, Urech TH, Pietz K. Will hypertension performance measures used for pay-for-performance programs penalize those who care for medically complex patients. Circulation. 2009 Jun 16;119(23):2978-85. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=19487595&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Current routine use" /></Field><Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use"><Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Ambulatory/Office-based Care" /></Field><Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Individual Clinicians or Public Health Professionals" /></Field><Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Unspecified" /></Field><Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Age greater than or equal to 18 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Either male or female" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care"><Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories"><Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Getting Better" /><FieldValue Value="Living with Illness" /></Field><Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" /><FieldValue Value="Equity" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure"><Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;12 months&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" /></Field><Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" /><FieldValue Value="Encounter" /><FieldValue Value="Patient/Individual (Consumer) Characteristic" /></Field><Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;All patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of hypertension seen within a 12 month period&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: See the original measure documentation for administrative codes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Documentation of medical reason(s) for not prescribing 2 or more anti-hypertensive medications (e.g., allergy, intolerant, postural hypotension) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Documentation of patient reason(s) for not prescribing 2 or more anti-hypertensive medications (e.g., patient declined) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Documentation of system reason(s) for not prescribing 2 or more anti-hypertensive medications (e.g., financial reasons) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Patients aged 18 years and older with a diagnosis of hypertension seen within a 12 month period with a blood pressure (BP)* less than 140/90 mm Hg OR patients with a blood pressure* greater than or equal to 140/90 mm Hg and prescribed** 2 or more anti-hypertensive medications during the most recent office visit&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: See the original measure documentation for related Current Procedural Terminology (CPT) Category II codes and list of medications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*BP value used for measure calculation:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot; class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Must be specified in medical record if &amp;gt;1 value (systolic/diastolic) recorded, and &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Must be value upon which treatment decision was based, and &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;May be obtained by measurement during office visit or review of a home blood pressure log, OR of a 24 hour ambulatory blood pressure monitor, but the value on which the treatment decision is being made and which might represent the average of more than 1 reading must be documented as such in the medical record. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;**Prescribed may include prescriptions given to the patient for 2 or more anti-hypertensive medications at most recent office visit OR patient already taking 2 or more anti-hypertensive medications as documented in the current medication list (each anti-hypertensive component in a combination medication should be counted individually).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Fixed time period or point in time" /></Field><Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Administrative clinical data" /><FieldValue Value="Electronic health/medical record" /><FieldValue Value="Paper medical record" /></Field><Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Adverse Health State" /></Field><Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Measure is disaggregated into categories based on different definitions of the denominator and/or numerator" /></Field><Field FieldID="3509" OrdBy="510" ID="607" Name="Basis for Disaggregation" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is disaggregated based on different definitions of the numerator. Report the number of patients for each numerator component separately AND a total:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients with a blood pressure &amp;lt;140/90 mm Hg &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients with a blood pressure &amp;ge;140/90 mm Hg and prescribed 2 or more anti-hypertensive medications during the most recent office visit &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" /></Field><Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" /></Field><Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information"><Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Measure #1: blood pressure control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="The Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&amp;#174; Measurement Sets" /></Field><Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="Hypertension Performance Measurement Set" /></Field><Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="American Medical Association on behalf of the American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association, and Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® - Clinical Specialty Collaboration" /></Field><Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p"><FieldValue Value="American College of Cardiology Foundation - Medical Specialty Society" /><FieldValue Value="American Heart Association - Medical Specialty Society" /><FieldValue Value="Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement® - Clinical Specialty Collaboration" /></Field><Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joseph Drozda, MD, FACC (&lt;em&gt;Co-Chair&lt;/em&gt;) (Cardiology; Methodology); Joseph V. Messer, MD, MACC, FAHA (&lt;em&gt;Co-Chair&lt;/em&gt;) (Cardiology); John Spertus, MD, FACC, FAHA (&lt;em&gt;Co-Chair&lt;/em&gt;) (Cardiology); Bruce Abramowitz, MD, FACC (Interventional Cardiology; Measure Implementation); Karen Alexander, MD, FACC (Cardiology; Geriatrics); Craig T. Beam, CRE (Patient Representative); Robert O. Bonow, MD, MACC, FAHA, FACP (Cardiology); Jill S. Burkiewicz, PharmD, BCPS (Pharmacy); Michael Crouch, MD, MSPH (Family Medicine); David C. Goff, Jr., MD, PhD, FAHA, FACP (Internal Medicine); Richard Hellman, MD, FACP, FACE (Endocrinology); Thomas James, III, FACP, FAAP (Health Plan Representative); Marjorie L. King, MD, FACC, MAACVPR (Cardiology; Cardiac Rehabilitation); Edison A. Machado, Jr., MD, MBA (Measure Implementation); Eduardo Ortiz, MD, MPH (Internal Medicine; Guideline Development); Michael O'Toole, MD, FACC (Cardiology; Electrophysiology; Measure Implementation); Stephen D. Persell, MD, MPH (Internal Medicine; Measure Implementation); Jesse M. Pines, MD, MBA, MSCE, FAAEM (Emergency Medicine); Frank J. Rybicki, MD, PhD (Radiology); Lawrence B. Sadwin (Patient Representative); Joanna D. Sikkema, MSN, ANP-BC, FAHA (Cardiology); Peter K. Smith, MD (Thoracic Surgery); Patrick J. Torcson, MD, FACP, MMM (Hospital Medicine); John B. Wong MD, FACP (Internal Medicine)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American College of Cardiology Foundation&lt;/em&gt;: Jensen S. Chiu, MHA; Kay Conley, RN, MSN, BC; Charlene L. May; Melanie Shahriary, RN, BSN&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Heart Association&lt;/em&gt;: Anne Leonard, MPH, RN, CCRC, FAHA; Mark D. Stewart, MPH; Gayle Whitman, PhD, RN&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;American Medical Association&lt;/em&gt;: Mark Antman, DDS, MBA; Heidi Bossley, MSN, MBA; Christopher Carlucci, MBA; Kerri Fei, MSN, RN; Bridget Gulotta, MSN; Kendra Hanley, MS; Karen Kmetik, PhD; Samantha Tierney, MPH; Chyna Wilcoxson; Temaka Williams, MPH, MBA; Greg Wozniak, PhD&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;National Committee for Quality Assurance Liaison&lt;/em&gt;: Manasi Tirodkar, PhD, MS&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Joint Commission Liaison&lt;/em&gt;: Millie J. Perich, MS, RN&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conflicts, if any, are disclosed in accordance with the Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&amp;reg; conflict of interest policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date"><FieldValue Value="2011 Jan" /></Field><Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement (PCPI) stipulates a regular review of measures (every 3-4 years), or when there is a major change in scientific evidence, results from testing, or other issues noted that materially affect the integrity of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;2014 Jan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement reaffirmed the currency of this measure in November 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The individual measure, &quot;Measure #1: Blood Pressure Control,&quot; is published in the &quot;Hypertension Performance Measurement Set.&quot; This document and technical specifications are available in Portable Document Format (PDF) from the American Medical Association (AMA)-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement&amp;reg; Web site: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.physicianconsortium.org&quot;&gt;www.physicianconsortium.org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For further information, please contact AMA staff by e-mail at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cqi@ama-assn.org&quot;&gt;cqi@ama-assn.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on December 19, 2011. The information was reaffirmed by the measure developer on November 30, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;copy; 2010 American College of Cardiology, American Heart Association and American Medical Association. All Rights Reserved. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CPT&amp;reg; Copyright 2009 American Medical Association&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production"><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;American College of Cardiology Foundation, American Heart Association, Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement®. Hypertension performance measurement set. Chicago (IL): American Medical Association; 2011 Jan. 27 p.  [24 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer"><Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the NQMC Inclusion Criteria which may be found at &lt;a href=&quot;../about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.qualitymeasures.ahrq.gov/about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" /></Field></Section></Version>
