<Version><xmlsource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Quality Measures Clearinghouse (NQMC).</xmlsource><Section SecID="560" OrdBy="10" Name="General"><Field FieldID="11" OrdBy="20" ID="561" Name="Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Smoking: the percentage of patients with any or any combination of the following conditions: CHD, PAD, stroke or TIA, hypertension, diabetes, COPD, CKD, asthma, schizophrenia, bipolar affective disorder or other psychoses who are recorded as current smokers who have a record of an offer of support and treatment within the preceding 12 months.&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="30" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;British Medical Association (BMA) and NHS Employers. 2014/15 general medical services (GMS) contract quality and outcomes framework (QOF): guidance for GMS contract 2014/15. London (UK): British Medical Association, National Health Service Confederation; 2014 Mar. 182 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field Name ="UMLS Concepts"><FieldValue Value="ICD9CM: Bipolar disorder, unspecified  (296.80); Chronic kidney disease, unspecified  (585.9); Complications affecting other specified body systems, not elsewhere classified, hypertension  (997.91); End stage renal disease  (585.6); Unspecified psychosis  (298.9); Unspecified schizophrenia, unspecified  (295.90)"/><FieldValue Value="MSH: Asthma ; Bipolar Disorder ; Coronary Disease ; Diabetes Mellitus ; Hypertension ; Ischemic Attack, Transient ; Kidney Failure, Chronic ; Lung Diseases, Obstructive ; Peripheral Arterial Disease ; Psychotic Disorders ; Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive ; Schizophrenia ; Smoking ; Smoking Cessation ; Stroke "/><FieldValue Value="MTH: Asthma ; Bipolar Disorder ; Cerebrovascular accident ; Cessation of smoking ; Chronic Kidney Diseases ; Chronic Obstructive Airway Disease ; Coronary heart disease ; Current Smoker ; Diabetes Mellitus ; Hypertensive disease ; Kidney Failure, Chronic ; Peripheral Arterial Diseases ; Psychotic Disorders ; Schizophrenia ; Smoker ; Smoking ; Transient Ischemic Attack "/><FieldValue Value="PDQ: smoking cessation intervention "/><FieldValue Value="SNOMEDCT_US: Asthma ; Bipolar disorder ; Cerebrovascular accident ; Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease finding ; Chronic renal failure syndrome ; Diabetes mellitus ; Hypertensive disorder ; Peripheral pulmonary artery disease ; Psychotic disorder ; Schizophrenia ; Smoker ; Smoking cessation assistance ; Transient cerebral ischemia "/></Field></Section><Section SecID="563" OrdBy="40" Name="Measure Domain"><Field FieldID="3025" OrdBy="50" ID="564" Name="Primary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Quality Measures: Process" /></Field><Field FieldID="3026" OrdBy="60" ID="565" Name="Secondary Measure Domain" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="566" OrdBy="70" Name="Brief Abstract"><Field FieldID="34" OrdBy="80" ID="567" Name="Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure is used to assess the percentage of patients with any or any combination of the following conditions: coronary heart disease (CHD), peripheral arterial disease (PAD), stroke or transient ischaemic attack (TIA), hypertension, diabetes, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), chronic kidney disease (CKD), asthma, schizophrenia, bipolar affective disorder or other psychoses who are recorded as current smokers who have a record of an offer of support and treatment within the preceding 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="21" OrdBy="90" ID="568" Name="Rationale" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The aim of this domain is to increase the proportion of successful smoking quit attempts by providing the best available support and treatment. A wide range of diseases and conditions are caused by cigarette smoking, including cancers, respiratory diseases, coronary heart disease (CHD) and other circulatory diseases, stomach and duodenal ulcers, erectile dysfunction (ED) and infertility, osteoporosis, cataracts, age-related macular degeneration and periodontitis. Women who smoke during pregnancy are also at substantially higher risk of spontaneous abortion (miscarriage) than those who do not smoke. Smoking can also cause complications in pregnancy and labour, including ectopic pregnancy, bleeding during pregnancy, premature detachment of the placenta and premature rupture of the membranes (National Institute for Health and Care Excellence [NICE], 2008).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2011, 20 per cent of the adult population of Great Britain were cigarette smokers. The overall prevalence of smoking has been at approximately this level since 2007 (Office for National Statistics [ONS], 2011). Around 33 per cent of the population of England tried to stop in 2011, but only two to three per cent of the population succeed in stopping (West, 2011). Many of these attempts fail because they are made without treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is good evidence to suggest that offering support and treatment is sufficient to motivate some smokers to attempt to stop who would not have done so with brief advice to quit alone. For example, a Cochrane review that included 132 trials of nicotine replacement therapy (NRT), with over 40,000 people in the main analysis, found evidence that all forms of NRT made it more likely that a person's attempt to quit smoking would succeed. The chances of stopping smoking were increased by 50 to 70 per cent (Stead et al., 2008).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;National Health Service (NHS) Stop Smoking Services combine psychological support and medication. Results for April 2012 to March 2013 showed that 724,247 people who had contact with the service had set a quit date. Four weeks later, 373,872 people had successfully quit (based on self-report) representing half of those who set a quit date (The NHS Information Centre, 2013).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;'An offer of support and treatment' means offering a referral or self-referral to a local NHS Stop Smoking Service adviser (who might be a member of the practice team) plus pharmacotherapy. Where such support is not acceptable to the patient, an alternative form of brief support, such as follow-up appointments with a general practitioner (GP) or practice nurse trained in smoking cessation, may be offered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The NICE public health guidance on smoking cessation (2008) states that healthcare professionals who advise on, or prescribe, NRT, varenicline or bupropion:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Offer NRT, varenicline or bupropion, as appropriate, to patients who are planning to stop smoking &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Offer advice, encouragement and support, including referral to the NHS Stop Smoking Service, to help patients in their attempt to quit &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;When deciding which therapies to use and in which order, discuss the options with the client and take into account:&#xA;    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Whether a first offer of referral to the NHS Stop Smoking Service has been made &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Contra-indications and the potential for adverse effects &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;The client's personal preferences &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;The availability of appropriate counselling or support &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;The likelihood that the client will follow the course of treatment &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Their previous experience of smoking cessation aids &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The guidance also states that managers and providers of NHS Stop Smoking Services:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Offer behavioural counselling, group therapy, pharmacotherapy, or a combination of treatments that have been proven to be effective &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Ensure clients receive behavioural support from a person who has had training and supervision that complies with the &quot;Standard for training in smoking cessation treatments&quot; (Health Development Agency [HDA], 2003) or its updates &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Provide tailored advice, counselling and support, particularly to clients from minority ethnic and disadvantaged groups &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Provides services in the language chosen by clients, wherever possible.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NICE public health guidance also states that stop smoking advisers and other healthcare practitioners who advise on, supply, or prescribe, pharmacotherapies should encourage people who are already using an unlicensed nicotine-containing product (such as unlicensed electronic cigarettes) to switch to a licensed product (2013).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to the potential for ex-smokers to resume smoking within three years of cessation, it is good clinical practice to ask patients with a history of smoking their current smoking status and offer treatment and advice where necessary. It is also good practice to ask and record the smoking status of newly registered patients and to offer support and treatment where necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to NICE public health guidance 1, 10, 45 and 48 for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This indicator relates to patients who are on the disease registers for CHD, peripheral arterial disease (PAD), stroke or transient ischemic attack (TIA), hypertension, diabetes, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), chronic kidney disease (CKD), asthma and mental health who are recorded as current smokers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Smoking is known to be associated with an increased risk of CHD.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN) clinical guideline 97, &quot;Risk estimation and the prevention of Cardiovascular disease (CVD) (2007),&quot; and the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) European Guidelines &quot;CVD Prevention in clinical practice (2007),&quot; for further information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;PAD is associated with older age and with smoking. Cigarette smoking is a very important contributor to PAD and as such the management of PAD includes smoking cessation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stroke or TIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;There are few randomised controlled trials (RCTs) of the effects of risk factor modification in the secondary prevention of ischaemic or haemorrhagic stroke. However, inferences can be drawn from the finds of primary prevention trials that cessation of cigarette smoking be advocated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to SIGN clinical guideline 108, &quot;Management of patients with stroke or TIA: assessment, investigation, immediate management and secondary prevention (2008),&quot; for further information. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypertension&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;There is no strong direct link between smoking and blood pressure. However, there is overwhelming evidence of the relationship between smoking and cardiovascular and pulmonary diseases. The NICE clinical guideline on hypertension (2011) recommends that patients who smoke are offered advice and help to stop smoking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diabetes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;The risk of vascular complications in patients with diabetes is substantially increased. Smoking is an established risk factor for cardiovascular and other diseases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COPD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Smoking cessation is the single most effective and cost-effective intervention to reduce the risk of developing COPD and stop its progression.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to NICE clinical guideline 101, &quot;Management of COPD in adults in primary and secondary care (2010),&quot; and the Global Initiative for Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease (GOLD) Guidelines for further information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asthma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;There are a surprisingly small number of studies on smoking related asthma.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting smoking as a teenager increases the risk of persisting asthma. One controlled cohort study suggested that exposure to passive smoke at home delayed recovery from an acute attack. Smoking reduces the benefits of inhaled steroids and this adds further justification for recording this outcome (Tomlinson et al., 2005). There is also epidemiological evidence that smoking is associated with poor asthma control (Price et al., 2005).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CKD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;There is good evidence from observational studies that patients with CKD are at increased cardiovascular risk and hence the rationale for including CKD here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schizophrenia, Bipolar Affective Disorder or Other Psychoses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Patients with a serious mental illness are far more likely to smoke than the general population (61 per cent of patients with schizophrenia and 46 per cent of patients with bipolar disorder smoke compared to 33 per cent of the general population). Premature death and smoking related diseases, such as respiratory disorders and heart disease, are however, more common among patients with serious mental illness who smoke than in the general population of smokers (McDonald, 2000).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3500" OrdBy="100" ID="569" Name="Evidence for Rationale" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;British Medical Association (BMA) and NHS Employers. 2014/15 general medical services (GMS) contract quality and outcomes framework (QOF): guidance for GMS contract 2014/15. London (UK): British Medical Association, National Health Service Confederation; 2014 Mar. 182 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Health Development Agency (HDA). Standard for training in smoking cessation treatments. London (UK): Health Development Agency (HDA); 2003 Jun. 28 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;McDonald C. Cigarette smoking in patients with schizophrenia. Br J Psychiatry. 2000 Jun;176:596-7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=10974973&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Clinical Guideline Centre. Hypertension. Clinical management of primary hypertension in adults. London (UK): National Institute for Health and Clinical Excellence (NICE); 2011 Aug. 36 p.&amp;nbsp;(Clinical guideline; no. 127).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE). Smoking cessation in secondary care: acute, maternity and mental health services. London (UK): National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2013 Nov. 68 p.&amp;nbsp;(Public health guidance; no. 48).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Institute for Health and Clinical Excellence (NICE). Smoking cessation services in primary care, pharmacies, local authorities and workplaces, particularly for manual working groups, pregnant women and hard to reach communities. London (UK): National Institute for Health and Clinical Excellence (NICE); 2008 Feb. 87 p.&amp;nbsp;(Public health guidance; no. 10).&amp;nbsp; [29 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Office for National Statistics. Chapter 1 - Smoking (General Lifestyle Survey Overview - a report on the 2011 General Lifestyle Survey). Newport, South Wales (UK): Office for National Statistics (ONS); 2013 Mar 7. 10 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Price D, Zhang Q, Kocevar VS, Yin DD, Thomas M. Effect of a concomitant diagnosis of allergic rhinitis on asthma-related health care use by adults. Clin Exp Allergy. 2005 Mar;35(3):282-7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15784104&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Stead LF, Perera R, Bullen C, Mant D, Lancaster T. Nicotine replacement therapy for smoking cessation. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2008 Jan 23;(1):CD000146. [277 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=18253970&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The NHS Information Centre, Lifestyles Statistics. Statistics on NHS Stop Smoking Services, England – April 2012 to March 2013. London (UK): The Health and Social Care Information Centre; 2013 Nov 30. 124 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Tomlinson JE, McMahon AD, Chaudhuri R, Thompson JM, Wood SF, Thomson NC. Efficacy of low and high dose inhaled corticosteroid in smokers versus non-smokers with mild asthma. Thorax. 2005 Apr;60(4):282-7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=15790982&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;West R. Key performance indicators: findings from the Smoking Toolkit Study. Smoking in England. 2011. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3022" OrdBy="110" ID="570" Name="Primary Health Components" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smoking; smoking cessation; coronary heart disease (CHD); peripheral arterial disease (PAD); stroke; transient ischaemic attack (TIA); hypertension; diabetes; chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD); chronic kidney disease (CKD); asthma; schizophrenia; bipolar affective disorder; other psychoses; support; treatment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="23" OrdBy="120" ID="571" Name="Denominator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients with any or any combination of the following conditions: coronary heart disease (CHD), peripheral arterial disease (PAD), stroke or transient ischaemic attack (TIA), hypertension, diabetes, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), chronic kidney disease (CKD), asthma, schizophrenia, bipolar affective disorder or other psychoses who are recorded as current smokers (see the related &quot;Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions&quot; field)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="24" OrdBy="130" ID="572" Name="Numerator Description" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of patients from the denominator whose notes have a record of an offer of support and treatment within the preceding 12 months &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="573" OrdBy="140" Name="Evidence Supporting the Measure"><Field FieldID="3027" OrdBy="150" ID="574" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Criterion of Quality for the Measure" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="A clinical practice guideline or other peer-reviewed synthesis of the clinical research evidence" /><FieldValue Value="A formal consensus procedure, involving experts in relevant clinical, methodological,  public health and organizational sciences" /><FieldValue Value="A systematic review of the clinical research literature (e.g., Cochrane Review)" /></Field><Field FieldID="3501" OrdBy="160" ID="575" Name="Additional Information Supporting Need for the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3072" OrdBy="180" ID="577" Name="Extent of Measure Testing" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="580" OrdBy="210" Name="State of Use of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3029" OrdBy="220" ID="581" Name="State of Use" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Current routine use" /></Field><Field FieldID="3030" OrdBy="230" ID="582" Name="Current Use" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="583" OrdBy="240" Name="Application of the Measure in its Current Use"><Field FieldID="3031" OrdBy="250" ID="584" Name="Measurement Setting" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Ambulatory/Office-based Care" /></Field><Field FieldID="3032" OrdBy="260" ID="585" Name="Professionals Involved in Delivery of Health Services" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3033" OrdBy="270" ID="586" Name="Least Aggregated Level of Services Delivery Addressed" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Practice or Public Health Sites" /></Field><Field FieldID="3505" OrdBy="280" ID="587" Name="Statement of Acceptable Minimum Sample Size" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Unspecified" /></Field><Field FieldID="41" OrdBy="290" ID="588" Name="Target Population Age" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="42" OrdBy="300" ID="589" Name="Target Population Gender" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Either male or female" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="660" OrdBy="310" Name="National Strategy for Quality Improvement in Health Care"><Field FieldID="3522" OrdBy="320" ID="661" Name="National Quality Strategy Aim" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3525" OrdBy="330" ID="662" Name="National Quality Strategy Priority" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Health and Well-being of Communities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Person- and Family-centered Care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prevention and Treatment of Leading Causes of Mortality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="590" OrdBy="340" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Health Care Quality Report Categories"><Field FieldID="3163" OrdBy="350" ID="591" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Living with Illness" /><FieldValue Value="Staying Healthy" /></Field><Field FieldID="3164" OrdBy="360" ID="592" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" /><FieldValue Value="Patient-centeredness" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="593" OrdBy="370" Name="Data Collection for the Measure"><Field FieldID="3506" OrdBy="380" ID="594" Name="Case Finding Period" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reporting year&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3054" OrdBy="390" ID="595" Name="Denominator Sampling Frame" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Patients associated with provider" /></Field><Field FieldID="3057" OrdBy="400" ID="598" Name="Denominator (Index) Event or Characteristic" Type="picklist-choice"><FieldValue Value="Clinical Condition" /></Field><Field FieldID="3058" OrdBy="410" ID="599" Name="Denominator Time Window" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="55" OrdBy="420" ID="596" Name="Denominator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Patients with any or any combination of the following conditions: coronary heart disease (CHD), peripheral arterial disease (PAD), stroke or transient ischaemic attack (TIA), hypertension, diabetes, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), chronic kidney disease (CKD), asthma, schizophrenia, bipolar affective disorder or other psychoses who are recorded as current smokers &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Refer to the original measure documentation for requirements for recording smoking status. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The disease register for the purpose of calculating Adjusted Practice Disease Factor (APDF) for SMOK002 and SMOK005 is defined as the sum of the number of patients on the disease registers for each of the conditions listed in the indicator wording. Patients with one or more co-morbidities, e.g., diabetes and CHD, are only counted once. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Exception reporting applies to indicators in any domain of the Quality and Outcomes Framework (QOF), where the achievement is determined by the percentage of patients receiving the specified level of care.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&quot;Exceptions&quot; relate to registered patients who are on the relevant disease register or in the target population group and would ordinarily be included in the indicator denominator, but who are excepted by the contractor on the basis of one or more of the exception criteria. Patients are removed from the denominator and numerator for an indicator if they have been both excepted and they have not received the care specified in the indicator wording. If the patient has been excepted but subsequently the care has been carried out within the relevant time period, the patient will be included in both the denominator and the numerator (achievement will always override an exception).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;Patients may be excepted if they fall within the strict criteria detailed below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol class=&quot;Note&quot; style=&quot;list-style-type: upper-alpha;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients who have been recorded as refusing to attend review who have been invited on at least three occasions during the financial year to which the achievement payments relate (except in the case of indicator CS002, where the patient should have been invited on at least three occasions during the period of time specified in the indicator during which achievement is to be measured [e.g., the preceding five years ending on 31 March in the financial year to which achievement payments relate]). &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients for whom it is not appropriate to review the chronic disease parameters due to particular circumstances, for example, a patient who has a terminal illness or is extremely frail. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients newly diagnosed or who have recently registered with the contractor who should have measurements made within three months and delivery of clinical standards within nine months, e.g., blood pressure or cholesterol measurements within target levels. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients who are on maximum tolerated doses of medication whose levels remain sub-optimal. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Patients for whom prescribing a medication is not clinically appropriate, e.g., those who have an allergy, contraindication or have experienced an adverse reaction. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Where a patient has not tolerated medication. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Where a patient does not agree to investigation or treatment (informed dissent) and this has been recorded in their patient record following a discussion with the patient. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Where the patient has a supervening condition which makes treatment of their condition inappropriate, e.g., cholesterol reduction where the patient has liver disease. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Where an investigative service or secondary care service is unavailable. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;Refer to the original measure documentation for further details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3507" OrdBy="430" ID="597" Name="Exclusions/Exceptions" Type="picklist-choice-4"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="59" OrdBy="440" ID="600" Name="Numerator Inclusions/Exclusions" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Number of patients from the denominator whose notes have a record of an offer of support and treatment within the preceding 12 months&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3061" OrdBy="450" ID="601" Name="Numerator Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Fixed time period or point in time" /></Field><Field FieldID="3062" OrdBy="460" ID="602" Name="Data Source" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Electronic health/medical record" /><FieldValue Value="Paper medical record" /><FieldValue Value="Registry data" /></Field><Field FieldID="3065" OrdBy="470" ID="603" Name="Type of Health State" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3066" OrdBy="480" ID="604" Name="Instruments Used and/or Associated with the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="605" OrdBy="490" Name="Computation of the Measure"><Field FieldID="3508" OrdBy="500" ID="606" Name="Measure Specifies Disaggregation" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Does not apply to this measure" /></Field><Field FieldID="3067" OrdBy="520" ID="608" Name="Scoring" Type="picklist-many"><FieldValue Value="Rate/Proportion" /></Field><Field FieldID="3068" OrdBy="530" ID="609" Name="Interpretation of Score" Type="picklist-one"><FieldValue Value="Desired value is a higher score" /></Field><Field FieldID="3090" OrdBy="540" ID="610" Name="Allowance for Patient or Population Factors" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="3070" OrdBy="560" ID="612" Name="Standard of Comparison" Type="picklist-choice-3"><FieldValue Value="not defined yet" /></Field><Field FieldID="71" OrdBy="570" ID="613" Name="Prescriptive Standard" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Achievement thresholds: 56% to 96%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="9" OrdBy="580" ID="614" Name="Evidence for Prescriptive Standard" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;British Medical Association (BMA) and NHS Employers. 2014/15 general medical services (GMS) contract quality and outcomes framework (QOF): guidance for GMS contract 2014/15. London (UK): British Medical Association, National Health Service Confederation; 2014 Mar. 182 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="615" OrdBy="590" Name="Identifying Information"><Field FieldID="73" OrdBy="600" ID="616" Name="Original Title" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;SMOK005. The percentage of patients with any or any combination of the following conditions: CHD, PAD, stroke or TIA, hypertension, diabetes, COPD, CKD, asthma, schizophrenia, bipolar affective disorder or other psychoses who are recorded as current smokers who have a record of an offer of support and treatment within the preceding 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="74" OrdBy="610" ID="617" Name="Measure Collection Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="Quality and Outcomes Framework Indicators" /></Field><Field FieldID="75" OrdBy="620" ID="618" Name="Measure Set Name" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="Smoking (SMOK)" /></Field><Field FieldID="16" OrdBy="650" ID="621" Name="Submitter" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="British Medical Association - Medical Specialty Society" /><FieldValue Value="National Health Service (NHS) Confederation - National Government Agency [Non-U.S.]" /></Field><Field FieldID="17" OrdBy="660" ID="622" Name="Developer" Type="orglist-p"><FieldValue Value="British Medical Association - Medical Specialty Society" /><FieldValue Value="National Health Service (NHS) Confederation - National Government Agency [Non-U.S.]" /></Field><Field FieldID="79" OrdBy="670" ID="623" Name="Funding Source(s)" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The expert panel who developed the indicators were funded by the English Department of Health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="80" OrdBy="680" ID="624" Name="Composition of the Group that Developed the Measure" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main indicator development group is based in the National Primary Care Research and Development Centre in the University of Manchester. They are: Professor Helen Lester, NPCRDC, MB, BCH, MD; Dr. Stephen Campbell, NPCRDC, PhD; Dr. Umesh Chauhan, NPCRDC, MB, BS, PhD.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Others involved in the development of individual indicators are: Professor Richard Hobbs, Dr. Richard McManus, Professor Jonathan Mant, Dr. Graham Martin, Professor Richard Baker, Dr. Keri Thomas, Professor Tony Kendrick, Professor Brendan Delaney, Professor Simon De Lusignan, Dr. Jonathan Graffy, Dr. Henry Smithson, Professor Sue Wilson, Professor Claire Goodman, Dr. Terry O'Neill, Dr. Philippa Matthews, Dr. Simon Griffin, Professor Eileen Kaner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="81" OrdBy="690" ID="625" Name="Financial Disclosures/Other Potential Conflicts of Interest" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None for the main indicator development group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="82" OrdBy="700" ID="626" Name="Endorser" Type="orglist"><FieldValue Value="National Health Service - National Government Agency [Non-U.S.]" /></Field><Field FieldID="19" OrdBy="730" ID="629" Name="Adaptation" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This measure was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3086" OrdBy="740" ID="630" Name="Date of Most Current Version in NQMC" Type="date"><FieldValue Value="2014 Mar" /></Field><Field FieldID="3511" OrdBy="750" ID="631" Name="Measure Maintenance" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="3512" OrdBy="760" ID="632" Name="Date of Next Anticipated Revision" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unspecified&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="20" OrdBy="770" ID="633" Name="Measure Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the measure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This measure updates a previous version: British Medical Association (BMA) and NHS Employers. Quality and outcomes framework guidance for GMS contract 2013/14. London (UK): British Medical Association, National Health Service Confederation; 2013 Mar. 203 p. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="14" OrdBy="780" ID="634" Name="Measure Availability" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The individual measure, &quot;SMOK005. The Percentage of Patients with Any or Any Combination of the Following Conditions: CHD, PAD, Stroke or TIA, Hypertension, Diabetes, COPD, CKD, Asthma, Schizophrenia, Bipolar Affective Disorder or Other Psychoses Who Are Recorded as Current Smokers Who Have a Record of an Offer of Support and Treatment Within the Preceding 12 Months,&quot; is published in the &quot;2014/15 General Medical Services (GMS) Contract Quality and Outcomes Framework (QOF): Guidance for GMS Contract 2014/15.&quot; This document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bma.org.uk/-/media/files/pdfs/practical%20advice%20at%20work/contracts/gpqofguidance2014-15.pdf&quot; title=&quot;BMA Web site&quot;&gt;British Medical Association Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="87" OrdBy="800" ID="636" Name="NQMC Status" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on December 16, 2013. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NQMC summary was updated by ECRI Institute on October 1, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field><Field FieldID="88" OrdBy="810" ID="637" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;No copyright restrictions apply. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="641" OrdBy="850" Name="Production"><Field FieldID="1" OrdBy="1366" ID="562" Name="Source(s)" Type="citation"><FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;British Medical Association (BMA) and NHS Employers. 2014/15 general medical services (GMS) contract quality and outcomes framework (QOF): guidance for GMS contract 2014/15. London (UK): British Medical Association, National Health Service Confederation; 2014 Mar. 182 p. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" /></Field></Section><Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer"><Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NQMC Disclaimer" Type="text"><FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Quality Measures Clearinghouse™ (NQMC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the measures represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All measures summarized by NQMC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public and private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, individuals, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Measures represented on the NQMC Web site are submitted by measure developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the NQMC Inclusion Criteria which may be found at &lt;a href=&quot;../about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.qualitymeasures.ahrq.gov/about/inclusion-criteria.aspx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;NQMC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or its reliability and/or validity of the quality measures and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of measures represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NQMC, AHRQ, or its contractor, ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of measures in NQMC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding measure content are directed to contact the measure developer.&lt;/p&gt;" /></Field></Section></Version>
